<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>QTB on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/qtb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in QTB on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 23:51:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/qtb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: thetrainline.com - &#39;Scale at speed&#39;</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/29/qtb-thetrainline-com-scale-at-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 23:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/29/qtb-thetrainline-com-scale-at-speed/</guid>
      <description>About 18 months on from the first ThoughtWorks QTB that I saw about offshoring, on Wednesday night I attended the latest QTB in Manchester titled &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/thetrainline.com-qtb[thetrainline.com - Scale at speed]&#39;.
 The presenters were thetrainline.com&amp;#8217;s CIO David Jack and the Managing Director of ThoughtWorks India, Mahesh Baxi.
 They took us on the journey that thetrainline.com have taken while working with ThoughtWorks to re-architect part of their system to allow them to quickly deliver new functionality on the 2,500 websites that their portal technology powers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 23:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch the latest ThoughtWorks Australia Quarterly Technology Briefing in Sydney on Wednesday where my colleague Lindy Stephens, Suncorp&amp;#8217;s Josh Melville and Lonely Planet&amp;#8217;s Nigel Dalton presented on &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/pdfs/aus-qtb-sept09.pdf[Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues]&#39;.
 I was actually unsure of how interesting it would be to me as the title seemed a bit dull but it was actually quite entertaining and not at all what I expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 23:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</guid>
      <description>I attended the most recent ThoughtWorks Quarterly Technology briefing on Tuesday which was titled &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/pdfs/aus-qtb-june09.pdf[Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up]&#39; and presented by my colleagues Andy Marks and Martin Fowler.
 There seems to be quite a few books out at the moment about how to introduce a more agile approach into your organisation - I&amp;#8217;ve been reading Lean-Agile Software Development and Becoming Agile and there is also a book called Scaling Lean and Agile Development - so I was intrigued to see whether the messages from this talk would be similar to those in these books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Lean Times Require Lean Thinking</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/qtb-lean-times-require-lean-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/qtb-lean-times-require-lean-thinking/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch the latest ThoughtWorks Quarterly Technology Briefing on Tuesday, which was presented by my colleague Jason Yip and Paul Heaton, titled &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/pdfs/aus-qtb-mar09.pdf[Lean Times Require Lean Thinking]&#39;
 I&amp;#8217;ve been reading quite a bit of lean related material lately but I thought it would be interesting to hear about it directly from the perspective of two people who have been involved with applying the concepts in organisations.
 What did I learn?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onshore or Offshore - The concepts are the same?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/24/onshore-or-offshore-the-concepts-are-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 07:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/24/onshore-or-offshore-the-concepts-are-the-same/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve never worked on a distributed or offshore project before, but intrigued having read about Jay Fields&#39; experiences I attended the &#39;OffShoring: The Current State of Play&#39; Quarterly Technology Briefing held this morning in Sydney to hear the other side of the argument.
 The underlying message for me was that a lot of the concepts we apply for onshore projects are equally important for offshore projects.
 Forrester&amp;#8217;s Tim Sheedy started off by providing some research data on the state of IT offshoring, some reasons he had identified around which type of work should be offshored before closing on some reasons that it might fail if not done correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>