<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiring on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/hiring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiring on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 03:50:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/hiring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewing: Communication</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/26/interviewing-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 03:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/26/interviewing-communication/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been in India for around 4 months and in that time I think I&amp;#8217;ve probably interviewed more people than I have in the last 4 years.
 Over this time I&amp;#8217;ve come to realise that the two main things I&amp;#8217;m looking for in candidates are passion and ability to communicate effectively.
 It&amp;#8217;s relatively easy to pick up on whether someone is passionate about what they do in a conversation or while pairing with them but I find the communication aspect a bit more tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making experience matter</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/23/making-experience-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/23/making-experience-matter/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across this post which speaks about the desire of recruiters to put candidates into technology specific boxes when it comes to describing their experience.
 I guess this desire is backed by humans&#39; need to see the patterns and similarities in data and having someone who doesn&amp;#8217;t quite fit into a generalised box makes it more difficult.
 I have worked on projects in Java, C# and a bit of Ruby so I do agree with most of the points with regards to language specialisation and as Jay Fields points out it is actually beneficial to diversify your experience to improve yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Developers - not just about the code</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/10/hiring-developers-not-just-about-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 01:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/10/hiring-developers-not-just-about-the-code/</guid>
      <description>It seems programmers are taking a bit of a hammering this week!
 Kris Kemper talks about the Net Negative Producing Programmer referring to a paper linked to by Jay Fields, concluding that the code submission is very important in helping to distinguish between good and bad candidates.
 Now I probably haven&amp;#8217;t done as many interviews at ThoughtWorks as Kris has but from what I&amp;#8217;ve seen of the recruitment process it seems to be more focused on ensuring that potential hires culturally fit into the organisation rather than that they write the best code that anyone has ever seen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>