<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Selenium on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/tag/selenium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Selenium on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 08:09:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/tag/selenium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium, Firefox and HTTPS pages</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2010/03/25/selenium-firefox-and-https-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 08:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2010/03/25/selenium-firefox-and-https-pages/</guid>
      <description>A fairly common scenario that we come across when building automated test suites using Selenium is the need to get past the security exception that Firefox pops up when you try to access a self signed HTTPS page.
Luckily there is quite a cool plugin for Firefox called &amp;lsquo;Remember Certificate Exception&amp;rsquo; which automatically clicks through the exception and allows the automated tests to keep running and not get stuck on the certificate exception page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build: Using virtual machines to run it in parallel</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/05/21/build-using-virtual-machines-to-run-it-in-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 18:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/05/21/build-using-virtual-machines-to-run-it-in-parallel/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on lately to improve the overall time that our full build takes to run is to split the acceptance tests into several small groups of tests so that we can run them in parallel.
We are using Cruise as our build server so the ability to have multiple agents running against different parts of the build at the same time comes built it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium - Selecting the original window</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2008/10/25/selenium-selecting-the-original-window/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 01:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2008/10/25/selenium-selecting-the-original-window/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve not used Selenium much in my time - all of my previous projects have been client side applications or service layers - but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a bit of time getting acquainted with it this week.
While activating some acceptance tests this week I noticed quite a strange error happening if the tests ran in a certain order:
com.thoughtworks.selenium.SeleniumException: ERROR: Current window or frame is closed! at com.thoughtworks.selenium.HttpCommandProcessor.doCommand(HttpCommandProcessor.java:73) at com.thoughtworks.selenium.HttpCommandProcessor.getString(HttpCommandProcessor.java:154) at com.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>