<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 16:18:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/category/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Documentation: The receiver decides if it&#39;s successful</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/07/28/product-documentation-the-receiver-decides-if-its-successful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 16:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/07/28/product-documentation-the-receiver-decides-if-its-successful/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations; Tell a story</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/14/presentations-tell-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 22:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/14/presentations-tell-a-story/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago before an F# talk that I gave at the .NET user group in Sydney my colleague Erik Doernenburg gave me some advice about how I should structure the talk.
(paraphrasing)If two people give a talk on the same topic they therefore end up being fairly similar talks even though each person may have a totally different perspective.
Erik suggested that people would find it much more interesting if I told a story about what I&amp;rsquo;d learnt about my topic (in this case F#).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Nic&#39;s &#39;How to stop killing people with your public speeches&#39;</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/16/dr-nics-how-to-stop-killing-people-with-your-public-speeches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 22:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/16/dr-nics-how-to-stop-killing-people-with-your-public-speeches/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a really cool blog post by Dr Nic titled &amp;lsquo;How to stop killing people with your public speeches&amp;rsquo; where he talks about the importance of practicing our presentations so that they actually make an impact on our audience.
Towards the end of the post he suggests joining Toastmastersas a useful first step for getting used to speaking to a group of people and as an added bonus you get feedback after each speech you give.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ladder of inference</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/04/24/the-ladder-of-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 14:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/04/24/the-ladder-of-inference/</guid>
      <description>In Discussing the UndiscussableWilliam Noonan describes the ladder of inference, a tool which can be used to help us achieve double loop learning with respect to our interactions with other people.
It also helps people understand how they interpret that information and how they apply their interpretation to the issue or problem at hand.
Essentially, the Ladder of Inference is a metaphorical tool designed to help people understand and describe their use of inductive reasoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of language: Intuitive</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/03/13/use-of-language-intuitive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 13:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/03/13/use-of-language-intuitive/</guid>
      <description>Sumeetand I were recently discussing the difference between the use of Google Groups for internal communication compared to the Jive platformwhich we&amp;rsquo;re now moving to and I suggested that I found the former more intuitive to use.
Sumeet suggested that the word &amp;lsquo;intuitive&amp;rsquo; is quite overloaded and later pointed me to an article on the Moodle websitewhich advocates the same thing:
It is generally accepted that a large part of usability is based on familiarity and experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pecha Kucha: My first attempt</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/pecha-kucha-my-first-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 04:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/pecha-kucha-my-first-attempt/</guid>
      <description>The first time I came across the Pecha Kuchastyle of presenting was at the XP 2010 conference during the Agile Suitcasesession where Pat Kuaand some others talked about the practices, principles and values they most favoured.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never done one before but as part of the preparation work for ThoughtWorks Universityeach of the trainers had to prepare one which we then presented to each other yesterday.
Despite the format being different than a normal presentation I still think the general idea of presenting any information applies - if you can tell it as a story then you have a much greater chance of keeping people&amp;rsquo;s attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Espoused theory, theory in action &amp; hypocrisy </title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/23/espoused-theory-theory-in-action-hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 01:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/23/espoused-theory-theory-in-action-hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in the year I wrote about Chris Argyris&amp;rsquo; espoused theory and theory in actionand one of the interesting aspects to it which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t previously considered is how we treat people when their espoused theory and theory in action don&amp;rsquo;t match.
My tendency is to think that these people are hypocrites but Benjamin Mitchellpointed out in a conversation on twitter that it&amp;rsquo;s not really helpful to think that way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication: Listening</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/20/communication-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 18:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/20/communication-listening/</guid>
      <description>I realised a couple of weeks ago while pairing with a colleague that I&amp;rsquo;ve become quite bad at interrupting people while they&amp;rsquo;re speaking.
I did have an inkling that I&amp;rsquo;d let my ability to properly listen to someone drift a bit but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen any evidenceuntil my colleague pointed it out.
Somewhat ironically I actually wrote a post about active listeningwhen I first started working at ThoughtWorks in 2006 and reading back over the listening barriers that I listed I realise that there are a few that I tend to break:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Why&#39; often unhelpful</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/03/why-often-unhelpful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 18:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/03/why-often-unhelpful/</guid>
      <description>Something which I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed recently in particular when interviewing people but also in some other situations is that frequently posing a question which begins with &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; results in quite a defensive response.
While discussing this with Priyankhe pointed out that asking a question in this way can often be construed as a criticism of the idea being questioned.
Admittedly it is often the case that I&amp;rsquo;m questioning something which has been done differently than what I might have done but I&amp;rsquo;m still curious as to the reasoning behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>While in India: Osmotic communication</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/while-in-india-osmotic-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 03:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/while-in-india-osmotic-communication/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that has been puzzling me during my time in India is the amount of time that is spent in meetings pushing information to people rather than them pulling it.
In previous projects that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a lot of the knowledge was moved between around as a result of osmotic communicationThis is normally accomplished by seating them in the same room.
Then, when one person asks a question, others in the room can either tune in or tune out, contributing to the discussion or continuing with their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication when it&#39;s not going your way</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/22/communication-when-its-not-going-your-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 23:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/22/communication-when-its-not-going-your-way/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading some of the articles written about the disruption caused by the snow across Europe and I found one quote in The Daily Telegraphby Phillip Hammond particularly interesting
I was stuck in Brussels Airport for almost a day and the communication by just about everybody there was as non existent as it sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s been at Heathrow.
I think part of the reason for that was that the people in charge didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was happening and part of it was because they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give people bad news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Communication: Learning models</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/27/team-communication-learning-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 10:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/27/team-communication-learning-models/</guid>
      <description>One of the problems I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed in several of the &amp;lsquo;agile&amp;rsquo; communication mechanisms (such as the standup or dev huddle) that we typically use on teams is that they focus almost entirely on verbal communication which only covers one of our learning styles - the auditory learning style.
The VAK learning style modeldescribes a simple model covering the different learning styles that people have:
My own learning style is predominantly visual so I tend to find that a well drawn diagram will help me understand something far more quickly than a colleague spending 10 minutes explaining something using only words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings: Guerilla Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/31/meetings-guerilla-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 14:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/31/meetings-guerilla-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned on twitter a few times my current team has a lot of meetings and apart from using the passive aggressive approach that Toby Tripp&amp;rsquo;s meeting tickerprovides I&amp;rsquo;ve also been flicking through Chapter 19, &amp;lsquo;Guerilla Collaboration&amp;rsquo;, of Jean Tabaka&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Collaboration Explained: Facilitation skills for software project leaders&amp;rsquo; which gives other ideas.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen some useful ideas that my colleagues have used in meetings that I&amp;rsquo;ve been part of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication: Logging levels</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/25/communication-logging-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/25/communication-logging-levels/</guid>
      <description>I think one of the most important skills to perfect when communicating with other people is to understand the level of detail that we need to be speaking at, something my colleague Ashwin Raghavrefers to as our logging level.
We log various things in our code at varying logging levels ranging from &amp;lsquo;error&amp;rsquo; through &amp;lsquo;debug&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;warn&amp;rsquo;, and each of these is useful for understanding what our code is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Builders hanging off class vs Builders in same namespace</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/15/builders-hanging-off-class-vs-builders-in-same-namespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 10:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/15/builders-hanging-off-class-vs-builders-in-same-namespace/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a couple of months ago about an approach we&amp;rsquo;re using to help people find test data buildersin our code base by hanging those builders off a class called &amp;lsquo;GetBuilderFor&#39;and I think it&amp;rsquo;s worked reasonably well.
However, a couple of weeks ago my colleague Lu Ningsuggested another way to achieve our goal of allowing people to find the builders easily.
The approach he suggested is to put all of the builders in the same namespace, for example &amp;lsquo;Builders&amp;rsquo;, so that if someone wants to find out if a builder already exists they can just type &amp;lsquo;Builders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding: Putting code where people can find it</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/02/coding-putting-code-where-people-can-find-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 23:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/02/coding-putting-code-where-people-can-find-it/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written about the builder patternwhich I think is a very useful pattern for helping to setup data.
It allows us to setup custom data when we care about a specific piece of data in a test or just use default values if we&amp;rsquo;re not bothered about a piece of data but need it to be present for our test to execute successfully.
One problem that I noticed was that despite the fact we had builders for quite a number of the classes we were using in our tests, when new tests were being added test data was still being setup by directly using the classes instead of making use of the builders which had already done the hard work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding humour to Tester/Developer collaboration</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/04/adding-humour-to-testerdeveloper-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 23:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/04/adding-humour-to-testerdeveloper-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>Pat Kua has a recent post where he talks about the language used between testers and developerswhen talking about defects that testers come across when testing some functionality and while I would agree with him that the language used is important, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found that injecting some humour into the situation takes the edge off.
As Dahlia points out I think this is probably only possible if there is good rapport between the developers and testers on the teamso perhaps this has been the case for the teams I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Productivity vs Individual Productivity</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/16/team-productivity-vs-individual-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 16:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/16/team-productivity-vs-individual-productivity/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Neal Ford&amp;rsquo;s The Productive Programmer(my review) which is a book all about improving your productivity as an individual developer.
It got me thinking that there are also ways that we can make teams more productive so that they are actually teams and not just a group of individuals who happen to work with each other.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity of working under some great TechLeadswho have helped create an environment where teams can perform to their maximum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of Crowds and groupthink in Agile Software Development</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</guid>
      <description>Gojko Adzicposted a summaryof a talk James Surowiecki gave at Agile 2008and it got me thinking how we use the Wisdom of Crowdsin Agile projects.
One of the most interesting things I learnt from the book is that when you bring together a diverse group of people, their output will probably be better than any one expert. Gojko points out this example that was used at Agile 2008:
There are a couple of areas of agile where I have seen how The Wisdom of Crowds can become groupthinkif we&amp;rsquo;re not careful:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Information Wall</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/20/the-information-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/20/the-information-wall/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the simplest things can provide the greatest value to project teams. We often look for a technical solution to problems where something simpler would achieve the same aim.
The Information Wall is as its name may suggest a place where you can put information that people in the team need to know but which they have not (yet) committed to memory.
Examples of things that you could put on an information wall could be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active listening</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/03/active-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/03/active-listening/</guid>
      <description>One of the first unusual (to me) things that I noticed from the trainers at ThoughtWorks University was that when they were listening to participants they would often ask questions and re-frame the participants&amp;rsquo; comments. Intrigued and impressed by this I spoke to one of the trainers and was told that they were engaging in &#39;active listening&#39;. Wikipedia defines the term as follows:
It reminded me of the 5th Habitthat Steven Covey speaks of in his book titled &#39;The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People&#39;: Seek First to Understand, Then to be Understood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>