<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 02:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docusaurus: Side menu on custom page</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/07/11/docusaurus-side-menu-custom-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/07/11/docusaurus-side-menu-custom-page/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been working with Docusaurus to build the dev.startree.ai website over the last few months and I wanted to add a custom page with a sidebar similar to the one that gets automatically generated on documentation pages. All the examples I could find showed you to create a splash page, so it took me a while to figure out how to do what I wanted, but in this post we&amp;#8217;ll learn how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>docker exec: Passing in environment variables</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/06/16/docker-exec-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/06/16/docker-exec-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been working on an Apache Pinot recipe showing how to ingest data from S3 and I needed to pass in my AWS credentials to the docker exec command that I was running. It wasn&amp;#8217;t difficult to do, but took me a little while to figure out.
  Figure 1. docker exec: Passing in environment variables  The command that I was running looked like this:
 docker exec \ -it pinot-controller bin/pinot-admin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: Find the network for a container</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2019/05/24/docker-find-network-for-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 06:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2019/05/24/docker-find-network-for-container/</guid>
      <description>If we want two Docker containers to communicate with each other they need to belong to the same network. In this post we&amp;#8217;ll learn how to find out the network of existing containers so that we can attach new containers to that network.
 All the containers mentioned in this post can be launched locally from Docker compose, using the following command:
 git clone git@github.com:mneedham/ksql-kafka-neo4j-streams.git &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd ksql-kafka-neo4j-streams docker-compose-up   Running this command will create four containers:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: Unknown - Unable to query docker version: x509: certificate is valid for</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2016/12/21/docker-unknown-unable-to-query-docker-version-x509-certificate-is-valid-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2016/12/21/docker-unknown-unable-to-query-docker-version-x509-certificate-is-valid-for/</guid>
      <description>I was playing around with Docker locally and somehow ended up with this error when I tried to list my docker machines:
 $ docker-machine ls NAME ACTIVE DRIVER STATE URL SWARM DOCKER ERRORS default - virtualbox Running tcp://192.168.99.101:2376 Unknown Unable to query docker version: Get https://192.168.99.101:2376/v1.15/version: x509: certificate is valid for 192.168.99.100, not 192.168.99.101   My Google Fu was weak I couldn&amp;#8217;t find any suggestions for what this might mean so I tried shutting it down and starting it again!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>