<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Objective C on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/category/objective-c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Objective C on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 18:27:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/category/objective-c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Objective C: Observations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/31/objective-c-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/31/objective-c-observations/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with Objective C over the last month or so and although my knowledge of the language is still very much limited I thought it’d be interesting to describe some of the things about the language that I think are quite interesting and others that keep catching me out.
Protocols I touched on protocols a bit in my first post but they seem like an interesting middle ground between interfaces and duck typing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective C: Expected &#39;(&#39; before &#39;Project&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/14/objective-c-expected-before-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 10:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/14/objective-c-expected-before-project/</guid>
      <description>A mistake I’ve made more than a few times while declaring headers in Objective C is forgetting to explicitly import the classes used in the interface definition.
I’ve been refactoring some of the code I wrote earlier in the week and wanted to create a &amp;#39;LabelFactory&amp;#39;. I had the following code:
LabelFactory.h
#import &amp;lt;UIKit/UIKit.h&amp;gt; @interface LabelFactory : NSObject { } + (UILabel*)createLabelFrom:(Project *)project withXCoordinate:(NSInteger)x withYCoordinate:(NSInteger)y; @end Which gives this error on compilation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective C: Back to being a novice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/06/objective-c-back-to-being-a-novice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 03:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/06/objective-c-back-to-being-a-novice/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post about parsing an XML file in Objective C I’m a novice on the Dreyfus Model when it comes to this type of development and I’ve found it interesting that I’ve dropped back into habits from my PHP days when I was first learning how to program.
The big picture My first instinct after I’d created a project in XCode was to try and understand how an iPad application fits together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective C: Parsing an XML file</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/04/objective-c-parsing-an-xml-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 05:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/08/04/objective-c-parsing-an-xml-file/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been wanting to try out some iPad development for a while and as a hello worldish exercise for myself I thought I’d try and work out how to parse the cctray.xml file from Sam Newman’s bigvisiblewall.
Realising that I’m a novice on the Dreyfus Model when it comes to Objective C I started out by following a tutorial from iPhone SDK Articles which explained how to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
