<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DuckDB on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/duckdb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DuckDB on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 02:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/duckdb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DuckDB/SQL: Get decade from date</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/04/20/duckdb-sql-decade-from-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/04/20/duckdb-sql-decade-from-date/</guid>
      <description>Working with dates in SQL can sometimes be a bit tricky, especially when you need to extract specific information, like the decade a date belongs to. In this blog post, we’ll explore how to easily obtain the decade from a date using DuckDB, a lightweight and efficient SQL database engine.
First, install DuckDB and launch it:
./duckdb Next, we’re going to create a movies table that has columns for title and releaseDate:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDB/SQL: Convert epoch to timestamp with timezone</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/04/05/duckdb-sql-convert-epoch-timestamp-timezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/04/05/duckdb-sql-convert-epoch-timestamp-timezone/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with the Citi Bike Stations dataset on Kaggle with DuckDB and ran into trouble when trying to convert a column containing epoch timestamps to a timestamp with timezone support. In this blog we’ll learn how to do that, which will at least be helpful to future me, if noone else!
The dataset contains 4GB worth of CSV files, but I’ve just downloaded a few of them manually for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Head to Head with DuckDB and Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/03/31/tennis-head-to-head-duckdb-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/03/31/tennis-head-to-head-duckdb-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we’re going to learn how to build an application to compare the matches between two ATP tennis players. DuckDB and Streamlit will be our partners in crime for this mission.
Set up To get started, let’s create a virtual environment:
python -m venv .venv source .venv/bin/activate And now install some libraries:
pip install duckdb streamlit streamlit-searchbox And now let’s open a file, app.py and import the packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDB/Python: Cannot combine LEFT and RIGHT relations of different connections!</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/03/20/duckdb-cannot-combine-left-right-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/03/20/duckdb-cannot-combine-left-right-relations/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with DuckDB over the weekend and ran into an interesting problem while using the Relational API in the Python package. We’re going to explore that in this blog post.
Set up To get started, let’s install DuckDB:
pip install duckdb And now let’s open a Python shell and import the package:
import duckdb Next, let’s create a DuckDB connection and import the httpfs module, which we’ll use in just a minute:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDB: Join based on maximum value in other table</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/02/01/duckdb-join-max-value-other-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/02/01/duckdb-join-max-value-other-table/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we’re going to learn how to write a SQL query to join two tables where one of the tables has multiple rows for each key. We want to select only the rows that contain the most recent (or maximum) value from that table.
Our story begins with a YouTube video that I created showing how to query the European Soccer SQLite database with DuckDB. This database contains lots of different tables, but we are only interested in Player and Player_Attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
