<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code-kata on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/code-kata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code-kata on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 07:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/code-kata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scala: Code Kata #2 - Karate Chop - Array Slicing Attempt</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/13/scala-code-kata-2-karate-chop-array-slicing-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 07:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/13/scala-code-kata-2-karate-chop-array-slicing-attempt/</guid>
      <description>In my continued attempts to learn a bit of Scala I’ve been trying out the 2nd of Dave Thomas&amp;#39; code katas - Karate Chop - while using an array slicing approach.
I’ve tried out the iterative approach to this problem in Java about a year ago and it ends up being quite verbose so I thought the array slicing one would be much more concise.
I didn’t drive any of the solutions I worked on from the tests - in fact I only got all the tests provided by Dave Thomas running right at the end which was probably a mistake in retrospect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from Code Kata #1</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/18/learnings-from-code-kata-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 19:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/18/learnings-from-code-kata-1/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading My Job Went To India and one of the chapters midway through the second section talks about the value of practicing coding using code katas.
I’ve not tried doing these before but I thought it would be an interesting activity to try out.
The Kata Code Kata One - Supermarket Pricing
What I learnt As this kata is not supposed to be a coding exercise I started out just modeling ideas in my head about how I would do it before I realised that this wasn’t working as an effective way for me to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
