<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/ipad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 07:18:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad: Getting PragProg books onto the Kindle App</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/16/ipad-getting-pragprog-books-onto-the-kindle-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 07:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/16/ipad-getting-pragprog-books-onto-the-kindle-app/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned previously I think the Kindle application on the iPad is the best one for reading books and as a result of that I wanted to be able to read some books which I&amp;rsquo;d bought from the PragProg store onto it.
The first step is to download the &amp;lsquo;.mobi&amp;rsquo; version of the book and use iPhoneExplorer to drag the file into the &amp;lsquo;Kindle/Documents/eBook&amp;rsquo; folder on the iPad.
This works fine but if you add more than one book in this way they all have the same cover image when viewed on the iPad which is quite annoying when trying to work out which book is which.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad: Redrawing the screen</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/09/ipad-redrawing-the-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 04:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/09/ipad-redrawing-the-screen/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in a post I wrote last week I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a little iPad application to parse a cctray feed and then display the status of the various builds on the screen.
The way I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this is by dynamically adding labels to the view and colouring the background of those labels red or green depending on the build status.
FirstViewController.h
@interface FirstViewController : UIViewController { ... NSMutableArray *dynamicallyAddedFields; }  FirstViewController.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad: First thoughts</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/21/ipad-first-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 21:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/21/ipad-first-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the iPad for about a month now and since my colleagues Martin Fowler, Neal Ford and Chris Stevenson have already previously written about their experiences with it I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share the way I&amp;rsquo;m using it as well.
Twitter I follow a lot of people involved in software development on twitter and come across a lot of interesting articles/blogs that people link to or write. A lot of the time I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to read those posts when I come across them - it would be much better if I could just save them to read later on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>