<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems Thinking on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/category/systems-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems Thinking on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 23:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/category/systems-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gaming the system: Some project examples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/10/26/gaming-the-system-some-project-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 23:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/10/26/gaming-the-system-some-project-examples/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year Liz Keogh gave a talk at QCon London titled &amp;#39;Learning and Perverse Incentives: The Evil Hat&amp;#39; where she eventually encouraged people to try and game the systems that they take part in.
Over the last month or so we’ve had two different metrics visibly on show and are therefore prime targets for being gamed.
The first metric is one we included on our build radiator which shows how many commits to the git repository each person has for that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Rationality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/06/26/bounded-rationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 17:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/06/26/bounded-rationality/</guid>
      <description>In Thinking In Systems: A Primer&amp;#39; one of the most interesting ideas that Donella Meadows describes is what Herbert Simon coined bounded rationality:
Bounded rationality means that people make quite reasonable decisions based on the information they have. But they don’t have perfect information, especially about more distant parts of the system
Later on in the chapter the following idea is suggested:
If you become a manager, you probably will stop seeing labour as a deserving partner in production, and start seeing it as a cost to be minimised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Traps: Rule Beating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/05/14/system-traps-rule-beating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 21:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/05/14/system-traps-rule-beating/</guid>
      <description>In &amp;#39;Thinking In Systems&amp;#39; section five focuses on systems which produce &amp;#34;truly problematic behaviour&amp;#34; and one of these so called system traps is known as &amp;#39;rule beating&amp;#39;.
Rule beating occurs when the agents in a system take evasive action to get around the intent of rules in a system:
The letter of the law is met, the spirit of the law is not.
A common system where we see this in organisations is around training budgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback Loops: Human Decisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/05/05/feedback-loops-human-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 18:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/05/05/feedback-loops-human-decisions/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading Donella Meadows&amp;#39; &amp;#39;Thinking In Systems: A Primer&amp;#39;, an introductory text on systems thinking, and after 30 pages or so the author poses the following challenge:
Sometimes I challenge my students to try to think of any human decision that occurs without a feedback loop - that is, a decision that is made without regard to any information about the level of stock that it influences
Meadows has quite a nice way of guiding us to thinking about systems by referring to &amp;#39;stocks&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;flows&amp;#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Argyris: Espoused Theory vs Theory in Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/01/13/chris-argyris-espoused-theory-vs-theory-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 20:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/01/13/chris-argyris-espoused-theory-vs-theory-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Via some combination of Christian Blunden, http://twitter.com/!/patkua[Pat Kua], http://twitter.com/!/dpjoyce[David Joyce] and Benjamin Mitchell I’ve been spending some time lately reading about the work of Chris Argyris.
I’ve previously come across his name while reading The Fifth Discipline but I didn’t realise how interesting his work actually is.
One of the interesting concepts I’ve come across so far is the difference between espoused theory and theory in use:
Espoused theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Thinking: Individuals and the environment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/11/23/systems-thinking-individuals-and-the-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/11/23/systems-thinking-individuals-and-the-environment/</guid>
      <description>Something which I’ve become fairly convinced about recently is that the environment that someone works in has far more impact on their perceived performance than their own individual skills.
Given that belief I’ve often got stuck answering why some people are better able to handle a difficult environment than others - in terms of accepting the situation and finding a way of being productive regardless.
Does this mean that they’re better than people who can’t work in that environment as effectively?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback loops: Overcompensating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/10/24/feedback-loops-overcompensating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 08:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/10/24/feedback-loops-overcompensating/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that I’ve noticed while working with various colleagues over the last few years is that the more experienced ones are much more skilled at making slight adjustments to their approach based on feedback that they receive from the environment.
I’ve been reading a couple of books on systems thinking over the last few months and one of the takeaways for me has been that we need to be careful when reacting to feedback we get from a system to ensure that we don’t over compensate and end up creating a new problem for ourselves instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
