<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leafletjs on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/tag/leafletjs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leafletjs on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 17:35:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/tag/leafletjs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet: Fit polyline in view</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2017/12/31/leaflet-fit-polyline-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 17:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2017/12/31/leaflet-fit-polyline-view/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been playing with the Leaflet.js library over the Christmas holidays to visualise running routes drawn onto the map using a Polyline and I wanted to zoom the map the right amount to see all the points. Pre requisites  We have the following HTML to define the div that will contain the map. &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;container&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;map&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;width: 100%; height: 100%&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;   We also need to import the following Javascript and CSS files: &amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;http://cdn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet: Mapping Strava runs/polylines on Open Street Map</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2017/04/29/leaflet-strava-polylines-osm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2017/04/29/leaflet-strava-polylines-osm/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a big Strava user and spent a bit of time last weekend playing around with their API to work out how to map all my runs.  Strava API and polylines  This is a two step process:   Call the /athlete/activities/ endpoint to get a list of all my activities For each of those activities call /activities/[activityId] endpoint to get more detailed information for each activity   That second API returns a &#39;polyline&#39; property which the documentation describes as follows:  Activity and segment API requests may include summary polylines of their respective routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet JS: Resizing a map to keep a circle diameter inside it</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2013/06/30/leaflet-js-resizing-a-map-to-keep-a-circle-diameter-inside-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 22:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2013/06/30/leaflet-js-resizing-a-map-to-keep-a-circle-diameter-inside-it/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been working on creating a UI to make searching for the football stadiums that I wrote about last week a bit easier and I thought I&#39;d give Leaflet JS a try.
Leaflet is a Javascript library which was recommended to me by Jason Neylon) and can be used as a wrapper around Open Street Map.
I started by creating a simple form where you could fill in a lat/long and distance and it would centre the map on that lat/long and show you a list of the stadiums within that diameter next to the map.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>