<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gladwell on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/gladwell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gladwell on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/gladwell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Outliersby Malcolm Gladwell
I came across this book following recommendations by Jason Yipand Steven &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; Liston Twitter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously read The Tipping Point and Blink and I like his easy going style so it was a no brainer that I was going to read this one.
I found that this book complimented Talent is Overratedquite nicely. Outliers covers how the story of how people became the best at what they do whereas Talent is Overrated focuses more on what you need to do if you want to become one of these people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearless Change: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 23:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Fearless Changeby Mary Lyan Manns and Linda Rising
I came across this book while watching an interview with Linda Rising on InfoQ. She mentioned some ideas from Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s The Tipping Pointwhich intrigued me and a strong recommendation from a colleagueensured this book made it onto my reading list.
I am not currently working on a project where I need to instigate a lot of change so I was going slightly against my own principle of only reading books when I need to, but I recalled several times previously when I have tried to introduce what I thought were good ideas and didn&amp;rsquo;t really get anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>