<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retrospective on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/retrospective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in retrospective on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 18:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/retrospective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Retrospective Handbook - Pat Kua</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 21:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Pat Kuarecently published a book he&amp;rsquo;s been working on for the first half of the year titled &amp;lsquo;The Retrospective Handbook&amp;rsquo; - a book in which Pat shares his experiences with retrospectives and gives advice to budding facilitators.
I was intrigued what the book would be like because the skill gap between Pat and me with respect to facilitating retrospectives is huge and I&amp;rsquo;ve often found that experts in a subject can have a tendency to be a bit preachy when writing about their subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focused Retrospectives: things to watch for</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/01/16/focused-retrospectives-things-to-watch-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 01:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/01/16/focused-retrospectives-things-to-watch-for/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago a slide deck from an Esther Derby presentation on retrospectiveswas doing the rounds on twitter and one thing that I found interesting in the deck was the suggestion that a retrospective needs to be focused in some way.
I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in a few focused retrospectives over the past 7/8 months and I think there are some things to be careful about when we decide to focus on something specific rather than just looking back at a time period in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective: The 5 whys</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/10/24/retrospective-the-5-whys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 22:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/10/24/retrospective-the-5-whys/</guid>
      <description>Last week my colleague Pat Fornasierran our team&amp;rsquo;s fortnightly retrospective and one of the exercises we did was &amp;lsquo;the 5 whys&amp;rsquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to see how the 5 why&amp;rsquo;s would pan out but could never see how you could fit it into a normal retrospective.
Pat was able to do this by using the data gathered by an earlier timeline exercise where the team had to plot the main events that had happened over the last 6 months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>