<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>altair on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/altair/</link>
    <description>Recent content in altair on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/altair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas: Compare values in DataFrame to previous days</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/21/pandas-compare-dataframe-to-previous-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/21/pandas-compare-dataframe-to-previous-days/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m still playing around with Covid vaccine data, this time exploring how the number of doses varies week by week. I want to know how many more (or less) vaccines have been done on a given day compared to that same day last week.
 We&amp;#8217;ll be using Pandas in this blog post, so let&amp;#8217;s first install that library and import it:
 Install Pandas pip install pandas   Import module import pandas as pd   And now let&amp;#8217;s create a DataFrame containing a subset of the data that I&amp;#8217;m working with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring England&#39;s Covid Vaccination Rates: The Data (cleanup)</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/17/england-covid-vaccination-rates-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/17/england-covid-vaccination-rates-the-data/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 13 months I&amp;#8217;ve spent countless hours looking at dashboards that showed Coronavirus infection rates, death rates, and numbers of people vaccinated. The UK government host a dashboard at coronavirus.data.gov.uk, which contains charts and tables showing all of the above.
 One thing I haven&amp;#8217;t been able to find, however, is a drill down of vaccinations by local area and age group. So I&amp;#8217;m going to try to build my own!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altair - Remove margin/padding on discrete X axis</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/02/altair-discrete-x-axis-margin-padding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2021/04/02/altair-discrete-x-axis-margin-padding/</guid>
      <description>One of the Altair charts on my Covid Vaccine Dashboards Streamlit app shows the % of first doses, but when I first created it there was some padding on the X axis that I wanted to remove. In this blog post we&amp;#8217;ll learn how to do that.
 Pre requisites Let&amp;#8217;s start by installing the following libraries:
 pip install pandas altair altair_viewer   Next let&amp;#8217;s import them, as shown below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Altair - Setting the range of Date values for an axis</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2020/01/14/altair-range-values-dates-axis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2020/01/14/altair-range-values-dates-axis/</guid>
      <description>In my continued experiments with the Altair visualisation library, I wanted to set a custom range of data values on the x axis of a chart. In this blog post we&amp;#8217;ll learn how to do that.
 We&amp;#8217;ll start where we left off in the last blog post, with the following code that renders a scatterplot containing the chart position of a song on a certain date:
 import altair as alt import pandas as pd import datetime df = pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Altair - TypeError: Object of type date is not JSON serializable</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2020/01/10/altair-typeerror-object-type-date-not-json-serializable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2020/01/10/altair-typeerror-object-type-date-not-json-serializable/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been playing with the Altair statistical visualisation library and recently ran into an error while trying to render a DataFrame that contained dates.
 I was trying to render a scatterplot containing the chart position of a song on a certain date, as seen in the code below:
 # pip install altair pandas import altair as alt import pandas as pd import datetime df = pd.DataFrame( [ {&#34;position&#34;: 2, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>