<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>youtube on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in youtube on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clustering YouTube comments using Ollama Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/27/clustering-youtube-comments-ollama-embeddings-nomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/27/clustering-youtube-comments-ollama-embeddings-nomic/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite tools in the LLM space is Ollama and if you want to learn how to use it, there’s no better place than Matt Williams&amp;#39; YouTube channel. His videos get a lot of comments and they tend to contain a treasure trove of the things that people are thinking about and the questions that they have. Matt recently did a video about embeddings in Ollama and I thought it’d be fun to try to get a high-level overview of what’s happening in the comments section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python-youtube: Retrieving multiple pages using page token</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/26/python-youtube-data-page-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/26/python-youtube-data-page-token/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with the YouTube API to analyse comments on YouTube videos and needed to use pagination to get all the comments. In this blog post, we’ll learn how to do that.
But before we do anything, you’ll need to go to console.developers.google.com, create a project and enable YouTube Data API v3.
Figure 1. YouTube Data API Once you’ve done that, create an API key.
Figure 2. Creating an API key Create an environment variable that contains your API key:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
