<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid-vaccines on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/covid-vaccines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid-vaccines on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/covid-vaccines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vaccinating England: The Data (cleanup)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/17/england-covid-vaccination-rates-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/17/england-covid-vaccination-rates-the-data/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 13 months I’ve spent countless hours looking at dashboards that showed Coronavirus infection rates, death rates, and numbers of people vaccinated. The UK government host a dashboard at coronavirus.data.gov.uk, which contains charts and tables showing all of the above.
One thing I haven’t been able to find, however, is a drill down of vaccinations by local area and age group. So I’m going to try to build my own!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas - Format DataFrame numbers with commas and control decimal places</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/11/pandas-format-dataframe-numbers-commas-decimals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/11/pandas-format-dataframe-numbers-commas-decimals/</guid>
      <description>I’m still playing around with the UK’s COVID-19 vaccination data and in this blog post we’ll learn how to format a DataFrame that contains a mix of string and numeric values.
Note On 10th November 2022 I created a video that covers the same content as this blog post. Let me know if it’s helpful 😊
We’ll be using Pandas&amp;#39; styling functionality, which generates CSS and HTML, so if you want to follow along you’ll need to install Pandas and Jupyter:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas - Dividing two DataFrames (TypeError: unsupported operand type(s) for /: &#39;str&#39; and &#39;str&#39;)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/08/pandas-divide-dataframes-unsupported-operand-type-str/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/08/pandas-divide-dataframes-unsupported-operand-type-str/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been doing some more exploration of the UK Coronavirus vaccine data, this time looking at the number of people vaccinated by Local Tier Local Authority. The government publish data showing the number of people vaccinated in each authority by age group, as well as population estimates for each cohort.
Having loaded that data into two Pandas DataFrames, I wanted to work out the % of people vaccinated per age group per local area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altair - Remove margin/padding on discrete X axis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/02/altair-discrete-x-axis-margin-padding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/04/02/altair-discrete-x-axis-margin-padding/</guid>
      <description>One of the Altair charts on my Covid Vaccine Dashboards Streamlit app shows the % of first doses, but when I first created it there was some padding on the X axis that I wanted to remove. In this blog post we’ll learn how to do that.
Pre requisites Let’s start by installing the following libraries:
pip install pandas altair altair_viewer Next let’s import them, as shown below:
import pandas as pd import altair as alt Visualising % of first doses Now we’re going to create a DataFrame that contains two columns - one contains the year and week number, the other the percentage of 1st doses administered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas: Filter column value in array/list - ValueError: The truth value of a Series is ambiguous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/03/28/pandas-column-value-in-array-list-truth-value-ambiguous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2021/03/28/pandas-column-value-in-array-list-truth-value-ambiguous/</guid>
      <description>The UK government publishes Coronavirus vaccinations data on coronavirus.data.gov.uk, but I wanted to create some different visualisations so I downloaded the data and have been playing with it in the mneedham/covid-vaccines GitHub repository.
I massaged the data so that I have rows in a Pandas DataFrame representing the numbers of first doses, second doses, and total doses done each day. I then wanted to filter this DataFrame based on the type of dose, but initially got a bit stuck.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
