<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dreyfus-model on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/dreyfus-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dreyfus-model on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 18:56:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/dreyfus-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning cycles at an overall project level</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/09/20/learning-cycles-at-an-overall-project-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 18:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2010/09/20/learning-cycles-at-an-overall-project-level/</guid>
      <description>I was looking back over a post I wrote a couple of years ago where I described some learning cycles that I’d noticed myself going through with respect to code and although at the time I was thinking of those cycles in terms of code I think they are applicable at a project level as well.
The cycles I described were as follows:
Don’t know what is good and what’s bad</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreyfus Model: More thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/08/10/dreyfus-model-more-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 20:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/08/10/dreyfus-model-more-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Since we discussed the Dreyfus Model in book club a few weeks ago I’ve noticed that I’m more aware of my own level of skill at different tasks and references to the model appear more frequent at least amongst my colleagues.
These are some of the things I’ve been thinking about:
How do we use the model? Alan Skorks has an interesting post where he discusses the role of the Dreyfus Model in helping to build software development expertise concluding that it doesn’t help very much in developing expertise within a team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: The Dreyfus Model (Stuart and Hubert Dreyfus)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/07/18/book-club-the-dreyfus-model-stuart-and-hubert-dreyfus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 10:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/07/18/book-club-the-dreyfus-model-stuart-and-hubert-dreyfus/</guid>
      <description>In our latest book club we discussed the Dreyfus Model, a paper written in 1980 by Stuart and Hubert Dreyfus.
I’ve become quite intrigued by the Dreyfus Model particularly since reading about its applicability to software development in Andy Hunt’s Pragmatic Learning and Thinking and after looking through Pat Kua’s presentation on &amp;#39;Climbing the Dreyfus Ladder of Agile Practices&amp;#39; I thought it’d be interesting to study the original paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferengi Programmer and the Dreyfus Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/02/13/ferengi-programmer-and-the-dreyfus-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2009/02/13/ferengi-programmer-and-the-dreyfus-model/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading Jeff Atwood’s post regarding Joel’s comments on the podcast about Uncle Bob’s SOLID principles and what struck me as I read through his dislike of having too many rules and guidelines is that there is a misunderstanding of how we should use these rules and I think at the heart of this understanding the Dreyfus Model might clear this up.
To briefly recap the different levels of the Dreyfus Model (you can read more about this in Pragmatic Thinking and Learning)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Learning and Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 02:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Pragmatic Learning and Thinking by Andy Hunt
The Review I came across this book when reading a post linking lean to the Dreyfus Model on Dan North’s blog.
I have a keen interest in theories of learning and have completed an NLP Practitioner’s course so the ideas described in the book summary immediately appealed to me.
After coming across the concept of Reading Deliberately in Chapter 6 of the book I decided I should give the SQ3Q approach to reading books its first run out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
