<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tensorflow on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/tensorflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tensorflow on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:31:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/tensorflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow 1.8: Hello World using the Estimator API</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/05/05/tensorflow-18-hello-world-using-estimator-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/05/05/tensorflow-18-hello-world-using-estimator-api/</guid>
      <description>Over the last week I&amp;#8217;ve been going over various Tensorflow tutorials and one of the best ones when getting started is Sidath Asiri&amp;#8217;s Hello World in TensorFlow, which shows how to build a simple linear classifier on the Iris dataset.
 I&amp;#8217;ll use the same data as Sidath, so if you want to follow along you&amp;#8217;ll need to download these files:
   iris_training.csv
  iris_test.csv
   Loading data The way we load data will remain exactly the same - we&amp;#8217;ll still be reading it into a Pandas dataframe:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow: Kaggle Spooky Authors Bag of Words Model</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/01/29/tensorflow-kaggle-spooky-authors-bag-words-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 06:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/01/29/tensorflow-kaggle-spooky-authors-bag-words-model/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been playing around with some Tensorflow tutorials recently and wanted to see if I could create a submission for Kaggle&#39;s Spooky Author Identification competition that I&#39;ve written about recently.  My model is based on one from the text classification tutorial. The tutorial shows how to create custom Estimators which we can learn more about in a post on the Google Developers blog. Imports  Let&#39;s get started. First, our imports: from __future__ import absolute_import from __future__ import division from __future__ import print_function import numpy as np import pandas as pd import tensorflow as tf from sklearn import preprocessing from sklearn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>