<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pomodoro on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/pomodoro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pomodoro on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 13:23:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/pomodoro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pomodoros: Just start the timer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2013/05/27/pomodoros-just-start-the-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 13:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2013/05/27/pomodoros-just-start-the-timer/</guid>
      <description>I wrote earlier in the year about my use of pomodoros to track what I’m doing outside of work and having done this for 6 months I noticed that I’m now procrastinating over picking something off the list to work on.
(I know…​I am awesome!)
I’m not sure whether this is because I don’t have anything really appealing on the list of things to work on or whether having so many things listed (I have 8-10 items) is causing the paralysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing around with pomodoros</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2012/01/22/playing-around-with-pomodoros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 21:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2012/01/22/playing-around-with-pomodoros/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 3/4 months I’ve been playing around with the idea of using pomodoros to track all coding/software related stuff that I do outside of work.
I originally started using this technique while I was doing the programming assignments for ml-class because I wanted to know how much time I was spending on it each week and make sure I didn’t run down rabbit holes too often.
One interesting observation that I noticed from keeping the data of these pomodoros was that while during the early programming assignments it would take me 7 or 8 pomodoros to finish, by the end it was down to around 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pomodoro: Observations from giving it a go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/02/20/pomodoro-observations-from-giving-it-a-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 19:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2011/02/20/pomodoro-observations-from-giving-it-a-go/</guid>
      <description>I learnt about the pomodoro technique a couple of years ago and while I did try it out sporadically back then, it’s only recently that I thought I’d properly give it a try when managing my spare time.
My approach without the pomodoro technique is to have a long list of things that I could do and then not really doing any of them because I feel bad about not doing one of the other things instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
