<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>functional-collection-parameters on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/functional-collection-parameters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in functional-collection-parameters on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 18:31:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/functional-collection-parameters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Collection Parameters: A different way of thinking about collections</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/18/functional-collection-parameters-a-different-way-of-thinking-about-collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 18:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/18/functional-collection-parameters-a-different-way-of-thinking-about-collections/</guid>
      <description>One of the changes that I&amp;#8217;ve noticed in my coding now compared to around 7 or 8 months ago is that whenever there&amp;#8217;s some operations to be performed on a collection I am far more inclined to think of how to do those operations using a functional approach.
 I&amp;#8217;ve written previously about the ways I&amp;#8217;ve been making use of functional collection parameters in my code but what I hadn&amp;#8217;t really considered was that the way of thinking about the problem we want to solve is slightly different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Collection Parameters: Handling the null collection</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/functional-collection-parameters-handling-the-null-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/functional-collection-parameters-handling-the-null-collection/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting cases where I&amp;#8217;ve noticed we tend to avoid functional collection parameters in our code base is when there&amp;#8217;s the possibility of the collection being null.
 The code is on the boundary of our application&amp;#8217;s interaction with another service so it is actually a valid scenario that we could receive a null collection.
 When using extension methods, although we wouldn&amp;#8217;t get a null pointer exception by calling one on a null collection, we would get a &#39;source is null&#39; exception when the expression is evaluated so we need to protect ourself against this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>