<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agile on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agile on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 23:08:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How we&#39;re using story points</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2012/10/21/how-were-using-story-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 23:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2012/10/21/how-were-using-story-points/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago Joshua Kerievsky wrote a post describing how he and his teams don&amp;#8217;t use story points anymore because of the problems they&amp;#8217;d had with them which included:
   Story Point Inflation - inflating estimates of stories so that the velocity for an iteration is higher
  Comparing teams by points - judging comparative performance of teams by how many points they&amp;#8217;re able to complete</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focused Retrospectives: things to watch for</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2012/01/16/focused-retrospectives-things-to-watch-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 01:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2012/01/16/focused-retrospectives-things-to-watch-for/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago a slide deck from an Esther Derby presentation on retrospectives was doing the rounds on twitter and one thing that I found interesting in the deck was the suggestion that a retrospective needs to be focused in some way.
 I&amp;#8217;ve participated in a few focused retrospectives over the past 7/8 months and I think there are some things to be careful about when we decide to focus on something specific rather than just looking back at a time period in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language of Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/30/the-language-of-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 03:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/30/the-language-of-risk/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago Chris Matts wrote an interesting blog post &#39;http://theitriskmanager.wordpress.com/2011/12/12/the-language-of-risk/[the language of risk]&#39; in which he describes an approach he used to explain the processes his team uses to an auditor.
  Why did the auditor like what I said? Because I explained everything we did in terms of risk. When they asked for a &amp;#8220;process&amp;#8221;, I explained the risk the process was meant to address. I then explained how our different process addressed the risk more effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: Getting overly focused on actions</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/09/24/retrospectives-getting-overly-focused-on-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 06:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/09/24/retrospectives-getting-overly-focused-on-actions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve attended a lot of different retrospectives over the last few years and one thing that seems to happen quite frequently is that a problem will be raised and there will become a massive urgency to find an action to match with that problem.
 As a result of this we don&amp;#8217;t tend to go very deeply into working out why that problem happened in the first place and how we can stop it happening in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing team sizes: Collective unresponsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/16/increasing-team-sizes-collective-unresponsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 18:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/16/increasing-team-sizes-collective-unresponsibility/</guid>
      <description>After a few recent conversations with colleagues as well as my observations of several projects I&amp;#8217;m coming to the conclusion that the way that people react in situations often differs significantly depending on whether they&amp;#8217;re working in a large or small team.
 One of the most obvious ways that this manifests itself is when there comes a need for someone to volunteer to take care of something - be it a particular functional area, communication with the onshore team or something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing team sizes: Boredom</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/27/increasing-team-sizes-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 22:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/27/increasing-team-sizes-boredom/</guid>
      <description>Although the majority of the teams that I&amp;#8217;ve worked on over the past few years have been relatively small in size I have worked on a few where the team size has been pretty big and perhaps inevitably the productivity has felt much lower.
 I think this is somewhat inevitable since although the overall throughput of these teams may be higher than on smaller teams, due to problems such as having difficulty parallelising work, not every pair is working at maximum productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Stories -  Negotiable</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/distributed-agile-stories-negotiable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/distributed-agile-stories-negotiable/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading an article about how to write meaningful user stories and towards the end of it the author mentioned the INVEST acronym which suggests that stories should be:
  Independent
  Negotiable
  Valuable
  Estimable
  Small
  Testable
   From what I&amp;#8217;ve seen the most difficult one to achieve in a distributed context is that stories should be &#39;negotiable&#39;, in particular when it comes to negotiating the way that the UX of a bit of functionality should work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical implementation heavy stories</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/13/technical-implementation-heavy-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 21:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/13/technical-implementation-heavy-stories/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I wrote about some of the problems that we can run into when we have implicit assumptions in stories and another problematic approach I&amp;#8217;ve seen around this area is where we end up with stories that are very heavily focused on technical implementation.
 Initially this seems like it will work out pretty well since all the developer then needs to do is follow the steps that have been outlined for them but from my experience it seems to create more problems than it solves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing team sizes: Parallelising work</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/26/increasing-team-sizes-parallelising-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 03:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/26/increasing-team-sizes-parallelising-work/</guid>
      <description>One of the trickiest things to do when working in bigger teams is ensuring that it is possible to parallelise the work we have across the number of pairs that we have available.
 From my experience this problem happens much less frequently in smaller teams. Perhaps inevitably it&amp;#8217;s much easier to find 2 or 3 things that can be worked on in parallel than it is to find 6 or 7 or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Increasing team sizes</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/14/agile-increasing-team-sizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 11:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/14/agile-increasing-team-sizes/</guid>
      <description>A fairly common trend on nearly every project I&amp;#8217;ve worked on is that at some stage the client will ask for more people to be added to the team in order to &#39;improve&#39; the velocity.
 Some of the most common arguments against doing so are that it will initially slow down the team&amp;#8217;s velocity as the new members learn the domain, code base and get to know the other members of the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Story Wall - A couple of learnings</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/22/agile-story-wall-a-couple-of-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 17:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/22/agile-story-wall-a-couple-of-learnings/</guid>
      <description>I wrote earlier in the week about the benefits of having a physical story wall on a distributed team and in the process of getting one in place on the project we learnt a few things that I&amp;#8217;d previously taken for granted.
 All the work in one place We initially started off by having stories on one part of the wall, bugs on another part and any technical tasks stored in Mingle somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Constraints</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/13/agile-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 14:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/13/agile-constraints/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across quite an interesting post written by Steve Garnett where he discusses the difference between constraints and impediments inside organisations.
 He comes to the following conclusion:
  For me, the difference between an impediment and a constraint is whether the individual, team, organisation, enterprise, or industry considers the obstacle as removable. If whoever is working with the obstacle believes it can be removed then it is considered an impediment, if the same person doesn&amp;#8217;t not believe it can be removed, or doesn&amp;#8217;t wish to work towards it&amp;#8217;s removal, it&amp;#8217;s considered a constraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: The curse of meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/09/agile-the-curse-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 03:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/09/agile-the-curse-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Something which can often happen with agile software development teams is that in the desire to take everyone&amp;#8217;s opinion into account for every decision we end up having a lot of meetings.
 Toni wrote about this a while ago and described a situation where he&amp;#8217;d managed to get rid of a meeting and just have a discussion after the stand up with the necessary people.
 While this is a good idea I still think there are occasions where it&amp;#8217;s not necessary to discuss every problem down to the minute details with the whole team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Developer attendance at showcases</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/27/agile-developer-attendance-at-showcases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 07:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/27/agile-developer-attendance-at-showcases/</guid>
      <description>On the majority of the projects that I&amp;#8217;ve worked on at ThoughtWorks we&amp;#8217;ve held a showcase at the end of each iteration to show our client what we&amp;#8217;ve been working on and finished over the previous one or two weeks.
 The format of these showcases has been fairly similar each time but the people who attended has tended to vary depending on the situation.
 As part of the project being worked on at ThoughtWorks University we&amp;#8217;ve run a showcase at the end of each week which the whole team have been attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing off a badly executed practice</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/17/writing-off-a-badly-executed-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 11:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/17/writing-off-a-badly-executed-practice/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an interesting post about pair programming by Paritosh Ranjan where he outlines some of the problems he&amp;#8217;s experienced with this practice.
 While some of the points that he raises are certainly valid I think they&amp;#8217;re more evidence of pair programming not being done in an effective way rather than a problem with the idea in itself.
 To take one example:
  Generally people don&amp;#8217;t think a lot while pair programming as the person who wants to think about the pros and cons will be considered inefficient (as he will slow down the coding speed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slack time</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/18/slack-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 17:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/18/slack-time/</guid>
      <description>Ken Schwaber recently wrote a blog post where he compared the differences between the kanban, lean and scrum approaches to software development and although I haven&amp;#8217;t had the same experiences as he has with the first two, one interesting thing he implies is that with a scrum approach we have slack time built in.
  God help us. People found ways to have slack in waterfall, to rest and be creative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Chasing a points total</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/05/11/agile-chasing-a-points-total/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 22:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/05/11/agile-chasing-a-points-total/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve previously written about the danger of using velocity as a goal but on almost every project I&amp;#8217;ve worked on at some stage we do actually end up chasing a points total.
 Something I find quite interesting towards the end of an iteration is that if there is a choice of two stories to pick up then the project manager will nearly always press for one which can be completed within the remaining time in order to get the points total for that iteration higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velocity as a goal </title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/07/velocity-as-a-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 23:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/07/velocity-as-a-goal/</guid>
      <description>Grant Joung wrote a post a while ago about velocity goals and whether they&amp;#8217;re a good or bad idea, a topic which seems to come up from time to time on agile teams.
 My colleague Danilo Sato previously wrote about the dangers of using velocity as a performance measure because it&amp;#8217;s something that&amp;#8217;s directly within our control and can therefore be gamed:
  Value should be measured at the highest level possible, so that it doesn&amp;#8217;t fall into one team&amp;#8217;s (or individual&amp;#8217;s) span of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the assumptions in stories</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/26/finding-the-assumptions-in-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 01:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/26/finding-the-assumptions-in-stories/</guid>
      <description>My colleague J.K. has written an interesting blog post where he describes a slightly different approach that he&amp;#8217;s been taking to writing stories to help move the business value in a story towards the beginning of the description and avoid detailing a solution in the &#39;I want&#39; section of the story.
 To summarise, J.K.&#39;s current approach involves moving from the traditional story format of:
 As I... I want.. So that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reminder about context switching</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/01/a-reminder-about-context-switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 23:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/01/a-reminder-about-context-switching/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve spent most of my time working on agile software development teams over the last few years so for the most part each pair is only working on one story, keeping the work in progress low and allowing them to focus on that piece of work until it&amp;#8217;s completed.
 My pair and I ended up in a therefore somewhat unusual situation last week where we were attempting to work on three things at the same time and weren&amp;#8217;t doing a particularly great job on any of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements: The story points focus</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/11/23/requirements-the-story-points-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 11:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/11/23/requirements-the-story-points-focus/</guid>
      <description>Something which an agile approach on a project typically gives us is the ability to change requirements rapidly based on the different types of feedback we typically get over the course of the project.
 One way that we can lose this advantage is by getting caught up by the number of story points being completed and using this as the measure of success.
 The flexibility to change has an impact on the number of story points that may be completed in a given iteration - if we start doing some work on a story and then get feedback from the business while it is still in progress it&amp;#8217;s possible that we will end up with more work to do than we had previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 23:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch the latest ThoughtWorks Australia Quarterly Technology Briefing in Sydney on Wednesday where my colleague Lindy Stephens, Suncorp&amp;#8217;s Josh Melville and Lonely Planet&amp;#8217;s Nigel Dalton presented on &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/pdfs/aus-qtb-sept09.pdf[Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues]&#39;.
 I was actually unsure of how interesting it would be to me as the title seemed a bit dull but it was actually quite entertaining and not at all what I expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 23:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</guid>
      <description>I attended the most recent ThoughtWorks Quarterly Technology briefing on Tuesday which was titled &#39;http://www.thoughtworks.com/pdfs/aus-qtb-june09.pdf[Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up]&#39; and presented by my colleagues Andy Marks and Martin Fowler.
 There seems to be quite a few books out at the moment about how to introduce a more agile approach into your organisation - I&amp;#8217;ve been reading Lean-Agile Software Development and Becoming Agile and there is also a book called Scaling Lean and Agile Development - so I was intrigued to see whether the messages from this talk would be similar to those in these books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Re-estimating cards</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/11/agile-re-estimating-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2009 07:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/11/agile-re-estimating-cards/</guid>
      <description>Chris Johnston has another interesting post in which he writes about the practice of re-estimating cards after they have been completed.
 I think this somewhat misses the point that the estimate is indeed supposed to be an estimate. It might turn out to be too optimistic or too pessimistic, the theory being that overall we will end up with a reasonable balance that will allow us to make a prediction on how much work we believe we can complete in a certain time period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: What is it?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/09/agile-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/09/agile-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Chris Johnston wrote recently about his experiences in agile software development, posing some questions that he has.
 Specifically:
   Why comments are evil?
  Why design is evil?
  Why must you pair all the time?
  Why Agile principles become Agile rules?
   Now I&amp;#8217;m assuming that most (if not all) of Chris&#39; experiences with agile have been at ThoughtWorks, in which case the mix of agile we use on our projects tends to be a combination of Scrum and Extreme Programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Why do we integrate early?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/06/agile-why-do-we-integrate-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/06/agile-why-do-we-integrate-early/</guid>
      <description>One of the inevitabilities of most projects is that at some stage there is going to need be some sort of integration.
 The likes of Alistair Cockburn in Crystal Clear and Andy Hunt/Dave Thomas in The Pragmatic Programmer talk of the need to do integration early rather than letting it wait until later, but why?
 Get the pain out the way To some degree every time we try to integrate there is going to be some level of pain - for me it therefore makes sense that we take this pain early on when we have the chance to do something about it rather than leaving it until later and being surprised at the problems it causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruise: Pipelining for fast visual feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/19/cruise-pipelining-for-fast-visual-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 21:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/19/cruise-pipelining-for-fast-visual-feedback/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool features in build servers like Cruise and Team City is the ability to create build pipelines.
 I have done a bit of work using this feature in previous projects but the key driver for doing so there was to create a chain of producers/consumers (producing and consuming artifacts) eventually resulting in a manual step to put the application into a testing environment.
 While this is certainly a good reason to create a build pipeline, a colleague pointed out an equally useful way of using this feature to split the build into separate steps pipelined together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: When is a story done?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/04/agile-when-is-a-story-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 22:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/04/agile-when-is-a-story-done/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve worked on a few different agile projects and one of the things that hasn&amp;#8217;t been completely consistent is when we consider a story to be &#39;done&#39;.
 There seem to a few different approaches, each of which has its benefits and drawbacks.
 Why do we care? We care about &#39;done&#39; for tracking the points we have achieved in an iteration and for knowing when we have added the value the story provides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Some misconceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/31/agile-some-misconceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 09:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/31/agile-some-misconceptions/</guid>
      <description>I came across an interesting article written for Visual Studio Magazine about agile methodologies where the author makes what I consider to be some misconceptions.
 The first is around the level of experience of people working on an agile team:
  For example, agile teams have a tendency to require a high level of experience and professionalism just to join the team.
   I wouldn&amp;#8217;t say I have a high level of experience and I&amp;#8217;ve been working on agile teams for the past two years, just one data point suggesting that this statement is not actually accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD: Does it make you slower?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/25/tdd-does-it-make-you-slower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 09:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/25/tdd-does-it-make-you-slower/</guid>
      <description>There have been several times where we have been writing code in a test driven way and it has been suggested that we would be able to go much quicker if we stopped writing the tests and just wrote the code.
 I feel this is a very short term way of looking at the problem and it does eventually come back to haunt you.
 One of the problems seems to be that in many organisations only the first release of a piece of software is considered, and in this case then yes maybe it would be quicker to develop code in a non TDD fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dave Thomas on Managing Lean and Agile In Large Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/05/dave-thomas-on-managing-lean-and-agile-in-large-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/05/dave-thomas-on-managing-lean-and-agile-in-large-software-development/</guid>
      <description>No coding dojo update this week as Dave Thomas was in the ThoughtWorks Sydney office to talk about Managing Lean and Agile in Large Software Development.
 It was actually a talk to the Geek Girls Sydney group but I sneaked in to hear his other talk after listening to the cloud computing one last week.
 It was a much toned down presentation compared to the cloud computing one although still amusing in places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile/Lean: All or Nothing?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/26/agilelean-all-or-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 06:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/26/agilelean-all-or-nothing/</guid>
      <description>While reading The Toyota Way one of the ideas which stood out for me was the constant mentioning of organisations which picked bits of The Toyota Way, implemented them, achieved some short term gains but then eventually these improvements and went back to the way they were before.
 I noticed a similar theme coming out in the series of posts in the last week or so about the decline of agile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: A reminder of the benefits of colocation </title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/22/agile-a-reminder-of-the-benefits-of-colocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 12:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/22/agile-a-reminder-of-the-benefits-of-colocation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it&amp;#8217;s the seemingly small details of the agile/XP approach to software development that make it so much more effective than the traditional approach.
 I was reminded of this last week with regards to having co-located teams with the developers, BAs, QAs and the business people all sitting in close proximity.
 I was working on the auto completion function for one of our screens and the QA on the team, who was sitting next to me, asked me if I could look through the acceptance criteria that he was working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standups: Pair stand together</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/standups-pair-stand-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 22:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/standups-pair-stand-together/</guid>
      <description>One of the common trends I have noticed in the stand ups of teams which practice pair programming is that very often the first person in the pair describes what they have been working on and what they will be doing today and then when it comes to the other person they say &#39;ditto&#39;.
 After I dittoed one too many times on a project earlier this year it was pointed out to me that this was not a valuable way of contributing to the weekend and that I should describe my view of our progress as it may differ to my pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile - Should everyone have to learn all the roles?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/agile-should-everyone-have-to-learn-all-the-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/agile-should-everyone-have-to-learn-all-the-roles/</guid>
      <description>In my final year of university a few years ago when I was applying for jobs I was really keen to join the (then) Reuters Graduate Technology program.
 The thing that appealed to me the most was that over the 2 years you were on the graduate program you would have the opportunity to be placed in 4 different roles within the business.	The website gives some examples:
  Technical architect, Project manager, Infrastructure service manager, Business analyst, Product &amp;amp; development manager, Software engineer, Implementation engineer, Desktop design consultant, Technical specialist, Deployment project manager, Training</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: The Client/User dilemma</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/12/agile-the-clientuser-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 07:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/12/agile-the-clientuser-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>While reading Marc&amp;#8217;s post about the Customer or Client naming dilemma I was reminded of another situation I have noticed in software development - the Client/User dilemma.
 From my experience of agile projects it tends to be much more likely that we can get easy access to our client than to the users of the system we are writing.
 Alistair Cockburn mentions in Crystal Clear that having an expert user sit with the team can be very useful, but it is not something that I have experienced on all the projects that I have worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Putting the risk up front</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/10/agile-putting-the-risk-up-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 22:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/10/agile-putting-the-risk-up-front/</guid>
      <description>The last two projects that I&amp;#8217;ve worked on I&amp;#8217;ve been on the project from right near the start, and one thing that&amp;#8217;s been consistent in both projects is that we&amp;#8217;ve spent time early on in the project trying to reduce technical risk.
 In my most recent project this has involved getting infrastructure in place early on, and in the previous one it involved working on technical spikes for several weeks to prove that what the client was asking for was actually technically possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: The Over Eager Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 23:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting situations that can arise when pair programming is that one person dominates the driving and their pair can hardly get a look in.
 This is not necessarily because they are hogging the keyboard - it is often just the case that they are the stronger technically in the pair and the other person isn&amp;#8217;t willing to ask for the keyboard.
 A big part of the value in pair programming comes from having both people taking turns at driving and navigating from my experience and there are several ideas that I have come across for trying to encourage a more collaborative approach to pair programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Clear: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 08:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Crystal Clear by Alistair Cockburn
   The Review This was a book which had been recommended to me by a colleague a few months ago as one of the best software development books to read, and after hearing Ian Cooper describe how his team was implementing some of the ideas at the Alt.NET conference I decided I&amp;#8217;d give it a read.
 I have been working in an Agile/XP environment at ThoughtWorks for the last two years so my context coming into the book was around understanding where the overlap with Crystal Clear was, what differences there are and how I can apply these on my projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Pair Flow</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/17/pair-programming-pair-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 00:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/17/pair-programming-pair-flow/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post about Team Productivity I stumbled upon the idea that while pair programming there could be such a concept as pair flow.
 The term &#39;flow&#39; is used to describe a situation where you are totally immersed in the work you&amp;#8217;re doing and where time seems to go by without you even noticing.
 This can also happen when pair programming and I think there are some factors which can make it more likely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Why would I pair on this?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</guid>
      <description>In the comments of my previous post on pairing Vivek made the following comment about when we should pair:
  The simplest principle I have is to use &#34;conscious&#34; pairing vs. &#34;unconscious&#34; pairing. A pair should always know why they are pairing.
   On previous projects I have worked on there have been several tasks where it has been suggested that there is little value in pairing. I decided to try and apply Vivek&amp;#8217;s principle of knowing why we might pair on these tasks to see if there is actually any value in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: What do we gain from it?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 22:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Vivek Vaid has an interesting post about parallel-paired programming where he talks about introducing lean concepts into deciding when we should pair to get maximum productivity.
 Midway through the post he mentions that the original reason that we starting pairing was for &#39;collaborative design&#39; which got me thinking whether there are reasons beyond this why we would want to pair.
 I have often worked on clients where the value of pair programming has been questioned and it has been suggested that we should only adhere to this practice for tasks where it adds most value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onshore or Offshore - The concepts are the same?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/24/onshore-or-offshore-the-concepts-are-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 07:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/24/onshore-or-offshore-the-concepts-are-the-same/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve never worked on a distributed or offshore project before, but intrigued having read about Jay Fields&#39; experiences I attended the &#39;OffShoring: The Current State of Play&#39; Quarterly Technology Briefing held this morning in Sydney to hear the other side of the argument.
 The underlying message for me was that a lot of the concepts we apply for onshore projects are equally important for offshore projects.
 Forrester&amp;#8217;s Tim Sheedy started off by providing some research data on the state of IT offshoring, some reasons he had identified around which type of work should be offshored before closing on some reasons that it might fail if not done correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of Crowds and groupthink in Agile Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</guid>
      <description>Gojko Adzic posted a summary of a talk James Surowiecki gave at Agile 2008 and it got me thinking how we use the Wisdom of Crowds in Agile projects.
 One of the most interesting things I learnt from the book is that when you bring together a diverse group of people, their output will probably be better than any one expert. Gojko points out this example that was used at Agile 2008:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perils of estimation</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/31/perils-of-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 00:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/31/perils-of-estimation/</guid>
      <description>I had my first opportunity to participate in release plan estimation over the last couple of weeks. I&amp;#8217;ve done estimation before but never at such a high level.
 When doing this it appeared clear that there were two situations that we were trying to avoid:
 Under estimating Under estimating is where we predict that the amount of time taken to complete a piece of work will be less than it actually is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile - Should we track more than just development?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/26/agile-should-we-track-more-than-just-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 23:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/26/agile-should-we-track-more-than-just-development/</guid>
      <description>I touched earlier on the transparency of agile and I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about some of the ways that we track/report information in agile projects.
 In all the projects I&amp;#8217;ve been involved in the data being tracked almost exclusively referred to development time. One of the advantages of having continuous analysis/development/testing is that we are able to reduce the time spent on the System Integration and User Acceptance Testing phases of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transparency of Agile</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/26/the-transparency-of-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 11:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/26/the-transparency-of-agile/</guid>
      <description>One of the key ideas behind agile software development is providing information as early as possible to allow the business to best make decisions.
 There are a variety of ways that this is done including the use of burn up charts, estimates of scope and velocity for example. This data is compiled to try and give an accurate idea of how long a project is likely to take so that the business can work out early on whether the value it adds is worth the expected cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Information Wall</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/20/the-information-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/20/the-information-wall/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the simplest things can provide the greatest value to project teams. We often look for a technical solution to problems where something simpler would achieve the same aim.
 The Information Wall is as its name may suggest a place where you can put information that people in the team need to know but which they have not (yet) committed to memory.
 Examples of things that you could put on an information wall could be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Junior/Junior pair</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 23:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to Pair Programming the Junior/Junior pairing is considered the most likely to lead to disaster. The old joke being that if you pair two Junior Developers together then you&amp;#8217;d better hope you have a revert function on your repository. But is this fair?
 Certainly pairing two Junior Developers together means that you automatically lose the value of the experience and mentoring skills that you would get if there was a Senior Developer as part of the pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Pairing with a QA</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/pair-programming-pairing-with-a-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/pair-programming-pairing-with-a-qa/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve talked about pair programming in some of my previous posts as I find the dynamic it creates quite intriguing.
 One idea which was suggested around the time I wrote those posts by my project manager at the time was developers pairing with the QA or BA on certain tasks. I didn&amp;#8217;t get to experience it on that particular project but over the last week I&amp;#8217;ve been doing quick a bit of build work and for some of that I was pairing with our QA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does generalising specialist mean you can&#39;t be the best?</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/does-generalising-specialist-mean-you-cant-be-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 05:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/does-generalising-specialist-mean-you-cant-be-the-best/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s often said that people who are really good at what they do are so good at it because they have narrowed their focus in their area of specialty until they are only doing the thing that they are good at.
 To use a football analogy, Manchester United&amp;#8217;s Cristiano Ronaldo - widely acknowledged as the best footballer in the world at the moment - is absolutely brilliant when he has the ball at his feet, taking on defenders, getting in shots around the opposition penalty area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: The Non Driving Pair</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/14/pair-programming-the-non-driving-pair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 01:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/14/pair-programming-the-non-driving-pair/</guid>
      <description>One of the intriguing aspects of pair programming for me is that of the non driving person in the pair&amp;#8201;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8201;what are they supposed to do?!
 Obviously there are fairly well known strategies for more interactive pairing, such as Ping Pong and Ball and Board (which is where one person controls the mouse and the other the keyboard), but neither of these strategies suggest what to do when you are not driving</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>