<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Batch Scripts on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://mneedham.github.io/tag/batch-scripts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Batch Scripts on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:10:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mneedham.github.io/tag/batch-scripts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting latest tagged revision in SVN from DOS/Batch script</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/16/getting-latest-tagged-revision-in-svn-from-dosbatch-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/16/getting-latest-tagged-revision-in-svn-from-dosbatch-script/</guid>
      <description>The way we have setup the build on our continuous integration server, Team City is configured to create a new tag every time the functional tests past successful on that machine.
We then have a QA and Showcase build that we can run to deploy all the artifacts necessary to launch the application on that machine.
Originally I had just written the batch script to take in the tag of the build which the user could find by looking through repo-browser for the last tag created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Else statements in batch files</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/13/if-else-statements-in-batch-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 22:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/13/if-else-statements-in-batch-files/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in a couple of earlier posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing quite a bit of work with batch files and the windows command line, and today I wanted to do an If Else statement in one of my scripts.
I thought it would be relatively simple, but after various searches and having read articles that suggested that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an ELSE construct in batch land I finally found a forum post which explained how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the current working directory from DOS or Batch file</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/12/getting-the-current-working-directory-from-dos-or-batch-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 22:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/12/getting-the-current-working-directory-from-dos-or-batch-file/</guid>
      <description>In the world of batch files I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying for ages to work out how to get the current/present working directory to make the batch script I&amp;rsquo;m working on a bit more flexible.
In Unix it&amp;rsquo;s easy, just call &amp;lsquo;pwd&amp;rsquo; and you have it. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting something that simple in Windows but it is! A call to &amp;lsquo;cd&amp;rsquo; is all that&amp;rsquo;s needed. If you need to set it in a batch script the following line does the trick:    ~~~  set WORKING_DIRECTORY=%cd%~~~    I was surprised that something so simple (I do now feel like an idiot) wasn&amp;rsquo;t easier to find on Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces in batch scripts</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/08/spaces-in-batch-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 20:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2008/08/08/spaces-in-batch-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Since reading The Pragmatic Programmer I&amp;rsquo;ve become a bit of an automation junkie and writing batch scripts falls right under that category.
Unfortunately, nearly every single time I write one I forget that Windows really hates it when you have spaces in variable assignments, and I forget how to print out a usage message if the right number of parameters are not passed in.
So as much for me as for everyone else, this is how you do it:   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 ~~~  @ECHO off IF [%1]==[] GOTO usage IF [%2]==[] GOTO usage  set VAR1=%1 set VAR2=%2  rem important client stuff  goto end  :usage echo Usage: script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>