<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiddler on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/tag/fiddler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiddler on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 23:25:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/tag/fiddler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiddler: Trying to work out how it all hooks together</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/09/06/fiddler-trying-to-work-out-how-it-all-hooks-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 23:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/09/06/fiddler-trying-to-work-out-how-it-all-hooks-together/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned previously that we&amp;rsquo;re making use of Fiddler quite a lot on my current project, mainly to check the traffic going to and from the service layer, and I&amp;rsquo;m quite curious how it actually works.
In particular I wanted to know:
 How we&#39;re able to route requests through Fiddler and then through the corporate proxy How proxy settings work differently for Firefox and Internet Explorer  As far as I&amp;rsquo;m aware the source code for Fiddler isn&amp;rsquo;t available so a colleague and I tracked the various proxy settings when Fiddler was turned on and off and also had a look at some registry settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Fiddler with IIS</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/06/24/using-fiddler-with-iis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 17:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2009/06/24/using-fiddler-with-iis/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been using Fiddler to debug the requests and responses sent via web services to a service layer our application interacts with and it works pretty well when you run the application using Cassini but by default won&amp;rsquo;t work when you run the website through IIS.
The key to this as one of my colleagues (who gives credit to Erik) showed me today is to ensure that IIS is running under the same user that Fiddler is running under which in our case is the &amp;lsquo;Administrator&amp;rsquo; account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>