<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twu on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/twu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twu on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 01:01:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/twu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Software Development journey so far</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/01/my-software-development-journey-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 01:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/01/my-software-development-journey-so-far/</guid>
      <description>While reading some of the rough drafts of Apprenticeship Patterns online I started thinking about the stages I have gone through on my Software Development journey so far.
I have worked in the industry for just over 3 years; 1 year at Reed Business and 2 years at ThoughtWorks. Over that time my thoughts, opinions and ways of doing things have changed, and no doubt these will continue to evolve as I learn more and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active listening</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/03/active-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 15:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/03/active-listening/</guid>
      <description>One of the first unusual (to me) things that I noticed from the trainers at ThoughtWorks University was that when they were listening to participants they would often ask questions and re-frame the participants&amp;rsquo; comments. Intrigued and impressed by this I spoke to one of the trainers and was told that they were engaging in &amp;lsquo;active listening&amp;rsquo;. Wikipedia defines the term as follows:   Active listening is an intent &amp;ldquo;listening for meaning&amp;rdquo; in which the listener checks with the speaker to see that a statement has been correctly heard and understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving effective feedback</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/02/giving-effective-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 03:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/02/giving-effective-feedback/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting things I have discovered since starting at ThoughtWorks earlier this month is the emphasis that is placed on giving feedback.
The first lesson we were taught about giving feedback was that it could be one of two types. Either it should Strengthen Confidence or Increase Effectiveness.
In Layman&amp;rsquo;s term that means that if you want to make a positive comment about somebody&amp;rsquo;s contribution then you should make reference to something specific that you believe they have done well so that they can continue doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance and Delegation</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/02/inheritance-and-delegation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 01:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2006/09/02/inheritance-and-delegation/</guid>
      <description>One of the major learning points this week at TWU has been understanding when it is appropriate to use inheritance and when delegation is the better choice.
I had heard stories about how inheritance could be misused but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I would be stupid enough to fall straight into that trap! We were taught the concept using &amp;lsquo;Measurement&amp;rsquo; as the problem domain. So to translate the previous sentence into English: The aim was to design classes which could handle old school measurement types such as Inches, Feet, Yards, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>