<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integration on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/integration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Integration on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 23:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding: Isolate the data not just the endpoint</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/coding-isolate-the-data-not-just-the-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 23:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/coding-isolate-the-data-not-just-the-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>One of the fairly standard ways of shielding our applications when integrating with other systems is to create a wrapper around it so that all interaction with it is in one place.
As I mentioned in a previous post we have been using the repository pattern to achieve this in our code.
One service which we needed to integrate lately provided data for populating data on drop downs on our UI so the service provided two pieces of data - a Value (which needed to be sent to another service when a certain option was selected) and a Label (which was the value for us to display on the screen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: Why do we integrate early?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/06/agile-why-do-we-integrate-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/02/06/agile-why-do-we-integrate-early/</guid>
      <description>One of the inevitabilities of most projects is that at some stage there is going to need be some sort of integration.
The likes of Alistair Cockburn in Crystal Clear and Andy Hunt/Dave Thomas in The Pragmatic Programmer talk of the need to do integration early rather than letting it wait until later, but why?
Get the pain out the way To some degree every time we try to integrate there is going to be some level of pain - for me it therefore makes sense that we take this pain early on when we have the chance to do something about it rather than leaving it until later and being surprised at the problems it causes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>