<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qcon on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://mneedham.github.io/category/qcon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qcon on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 09:45:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mneedham.github.io/category/qcon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2009: The Power of Value - Power Use of Value Objects in Domain Driven Design - Dan Bergh Johnsson</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/15/qcon-london-2009-the-power-of-value-power-use-of-value-objects-in-domain-driven-design-dan-bergh-johnsson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 09:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/15/qcon-london-2009-the-power-of-value-power-use-of-value-objects-in-domain-driven-design-dan-bergh-johnsson/</guid>
      <description>The final Domain Driven Design talk I attended at QCon was by Dan Bergh Johnsson about the importance of value objects in our code.
I thought this session fitted in really well as a couple of the previous speakers had spoken of the under utilisation of value objects.
The slides for the presentation are here.
What did I learn?  Dan started the talk by outlining the goal for the presentation which was to &#39;show how power use of value objects can radically change design and code, hopefully for the better&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2009: Rebuilding guardian.co.uk with DDD - Phil Wills</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/14/qcon-london-2009-rebuilding-guardiancouk-with-ddd-phil-wills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 14:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/14/qcon-london-2009-rebuilding-guardiancouk-with-ddd-phil-wills/</guid>
      <description>Talk #3 on the Domain Driven Design track at QCon was by Phil Wills about how the Guardian rebuilt their website using Domain Driven Design.
I&amp;rsquo;d heard a little bit about this beforehand from colleagues who had the chance to work on that project but it seemed like a good opportunity to hear a practical example and the lessons learned along the way.
There are no slides available for this one on the QCon website at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2009: DDD &amp; BDD - Dan North</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/14/qcon-london-2009-ddd-bdd-dan-north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 01:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/14/qcon-london-2009-ddd-bdd-dan-north/</guid>
      <description>The second presentation in the Domain Driven Design track at QCon was titled &amp;lsquo;DDD &amp;amp; BDD&amp;rsquo; and was presented by my colleague Dan North - a late stand in for Greg Young who apparently injured himself playing ice hockey.
Eric did an interview with Greg at QCon San Francisco 2007 where Greg talks about some of his ideas and apparently there is an InfoQ video kicking around of Greg&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Unshackle Your Domain&amp;rsquo; talk from QCon San Francisco 2008 which we were told to pester InfoQ to post on their website!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon London 2009: What I&#39;ve learned about DDD since the book - Eric Evans</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/13/qcon-london-2009-what-ive-learned-about-ddd-since-the-book-eric-evans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 20:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2009/03/13/qcon-london-2009-what-ive-learned-about-ddd-since-the-book-eric-evans/</guid>
      <description>I went to the QCon conference in London on Thursday, spending the majority of the day on Eric Evans&amp;rsquo; Domain Driven Design track.
The opening presentation was by Eric Evans, himself, and was titled &amp;lsquo;What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about DDD since the book&amp;rsquo;.
 In the 5 years since the book was published, I&#39;ve practiced DDD on various client projects, and I&#39;ve continued to learn about what works, what doesn&#39;t work, and how to conceptualize and describe it all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>