<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xpday on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/xpday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xpday on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 02:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/xpday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Visualizing what&#39;s happening on our project</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/30/xp-day-visualizing-whats-happening-on-our-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 02:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/30/xp-day-visualizing-whats-happening-on-our-project/</guid>
      <description>Another presentation that I gave at XP Day was one covering some visualisations Liz, Udayand I have created from various data we have about our project, gathered from Git, Go and Mingle.
These were some of the things that I learned from doing the presentation:
As a result it was necessary to scroll up and down/side to side when demonstrating each visualisationso that people could actually see them.
Either I need to work out how to get the resolution of the projector higher or be able to shrink the images to the right size so they&amp;rsquo;d fit more naturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Scala: An Experience Report (Liz Douglass and me)</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-scala-an-experience-report-liz-douglass-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 23:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-scala-an-experience-report-liz-douglass-and-me/</guid>
      <description>At XP Day my colleague Liz Douglassand I presented the following experience report on our last 6 months working together on our project.
We wanted to focus on answering the following questions with our talk:
We covered the testing approach we&amp;rsquo;ve taken, our transition from using Mustacheas our templating language to using Jadeand the different features of the language and how we&amp;rsquo;ve been using/abusing them.
The approach we used while presenting was to cover each topic in chronological ordersuch that we showed how the code had evolved from June until November and the things we&amp;rsquo;d learned over that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Cynefin &amp; Agile (Joseph Pelrine/Steve Freeman)</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-cynefin-agile-joseph-pelrinesteve-freeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 22:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-cynefin-agile-joseph-pelrinesteve-freeman/</guid>
      <description>Another session that I attended at XP Day was one facilitated by Steve Freemanand Joseph Pelrinewhere we discussed the Cynefin model, something that I first came across earlier in the year at XP 2011.
We spent the first part of the session drawing out the model and coming up with some software examples which might fit into each domain.
Steve pointed out that with simple/complicated the important thing to remember is that things on the right hand side are repeatablewhereas on the other side we could do the same thing again and get a completely different result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Refactoring to functional style (Julian Kelsey/Andrew Parker)</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/22/xp-day-refactoring-to-functional-style-julian-kelseyandrew-parker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/22/xp-day-refactoring-to-functional-style-julian-kelseyandrew-parker/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m attending XP Daythis year and the first talk I attended was one by Julian Kelseyand Andrew Parkertitled &amp;lsquo;Refactoring to functional style&amp;rsquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a Scala project for the last 6 months and previously given a coupleof talksabout adopting a functional style of programming in C# so this is a subject area that I find quite interesting.
The talk focused on 5 refactorings that the presenters have identified to help move imperative code to a more functional style:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>