<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xp on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/xp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xp on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 12:46:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/xp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile: A reminder of the benefits of colocation </title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/22/agile-a-reminder-of-the-benefits-of-colocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 12:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/22/agile-a-reminder-of-the-benefits-of-colocation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s the seemingly small details of the agile/XP approach to software development that make it so much more effective than the traditional approach.
I was reminded of this last week with regards to having co-located teams with the developers, BAs, QAs and the business people all sitting in close proximity.
I was working on the auto completion function for one of our screens and the QA on the team, who was sitting next to me, asked me if I could look through the acceptance criteria that he was working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standups: Pair stand together</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/standups-pair-stand-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 22:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/17/standups-pair-stand-together/</guid>
      <description>One of the common trends I have noticed in the stand ups of teams which practice pair programming is that very often the first person in the pair describes what they have been working on and what they will be doing today and then when it comes to the other person they say &amp;lsquo;ditto&amp;rsquo;.
After I dittoed one too many times on a project earlier this year it was pointed out to me that this was not a valuable way of contributing to the weekend and that I should describe my view of our progress as it may differ to my pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: The Over Eager Driver</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 23:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting situations that can arise when pair programming is that one person dominates the driving and their pair can hardly get a look in.
This is not necessarily because they are hogging the keyboard - it is often just the case that they are the stronger technically in the pair and the other person isn&amp;rsquo;t willing to ask for the keyboard.
A big part of the value in pair programming comes from having both people taking turns at driving and navigating from my experience and there are several ideas that I have come across for trying to encourage a more collaborative approach to pair programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Clear: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 08:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Crystal Clear by Alistair Cockburn
The Review This was a book which had been recommended to me by a colleague a few months ago as one of the best software development books to read, and after hearing Ian Cooper describe how his team was implementing some of the ideas at the Alt.NET conference I decided I&amp;rsquo;d give it a read.
I have been working in an Agile/XP environment at ThoughtWorks for the last two years so my context coming into the book was around understanding where the overlap with Crystal Clear was, what differences there are and how I can apply these on my projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Why would I pair on this?</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</guid>
      <description>In the comments of my previous post on pairing Vivek made the following comment about when we should pair:
 The simplest principle I have is to use &#34;conscious&#34; pairing vs. &#34;unconscious&#34; pairing. A pair should always *know* why they are pairing.  On previous projects I have worked on there have been several tasks where it has been suggested that there is little value in pairing. I decided to try and apply Vivek&amp;rsquo;s principle of knowing why we might pair on these tasks to see if there is actually any value in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: What do we gain from it?</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 22:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Vivek Vaid has an interesting post about parallel-paired programming where he talks about introducing lean concepts into deciding when we should pair to get maximum productivity.
Midway through the post he mentions that the original reason that we starting pairing was for &amp;lsquo;collaborative design&amp;rsquo; which got me thinking whether there are reasons beyond this why we would want to pair.
I have often worked on clients where the value of pair programming has been questioned and it has been suggested that we should only adhere to this practice for tasks where it adds most value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Junior/Junior pair</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 23:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to Pair Programming the Junior/Junior pairing is considered the most likely to lead to disaster. The old joke being that if you pair two Junior Developers together then you&amp;rsquo;d better hope you have a revert function on your repository. But is this fair?
Certainly pairing two Junior Developers together means that you automatically lose the value of the experience and mentoring skills that you would get if there was a Senior Developer as part of the pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Introduction</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 01:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had the opportunity to have worked with many different people pair programming wise over the last year or so, and having seen it done in several different ways thought it would be interesting to work through some of my thoughts about this Extreme Programming (XP) originated practice.
First of all it seems to me that pair programming is a technique that is used with a lot more frequency at ThoughtWorks than at any other IT organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>