<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughtworks University on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://mneedham.github.io/category/thoughtworks-university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughtworks University on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 11:25:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mneedham.github.io/category/thoughtworks-university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Retrospective Coherence</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/05/01/thoughtworks-university-retrospective-coherence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 11:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/05/01/thoughtworks-university-retrospective-coherence/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across Joseph Pelrine&amp;rsquo;s blog post where he describes the way that you might go about organising a great party.
He describes a party that a friend of his hosted and all the things which contributed to it being great, such as the people you invite, the music that is played, the food and drink that are served and the conversations that are had.
If you then wanted to replicate a &amp;lsquo;great party&amp;rsquo; you might think that you could just replay his friend&amp;rsquo;s party, with the same guests, same music, a script of the conversations had and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: v2.0 vs v1.0</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/27/thoughtworks-university-v2-0-vs-v1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 12:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/27/thoughtworks-university-v2-0-vs-v1-0/</guid>
      <description>Since we finished the most recent ThoughtWorks University session last week a few people have been asking me how the experience was and I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself comparing this experience to my own as an attendee in August 2006.
Back then ThoughtWorks University was much different. We had 5 weeks of workshop style sessions and then spent the last week working on an internal application.
This time we spent 1 week doing the workshop style sessions, 1 week working together on a story and then 4 weeks working on the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Things people found difficult</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/23/thoughtworks-university-things-people-found-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 19:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/23/thoughtworks-university-things-people-found-difficult/</guid>
      <description>After six weeks ThoughtWorks University #21 finished on Thursday so I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to summarise some of the things that people seemed to find difficult over the course of TWU.
The stack trace We were using Java for the duration of TWU and as a result there were plenty of stack traces for people to debug.
These were most frequently related to incorrect wiring of Spring components but there were other reasons too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: &#34;It&#39;s your project&#34;</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/13/thoughtworks-university-its-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 20:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/13/thoughtworks-university-its-your-project/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that we&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with at ThoughtWorks University is giving the attendees the opportunity to run the project that we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.
The first few weeks were the most frustrating both for the trainers and for the attendees because we spent a lot of time telling the attendees that it was their project but then didn&amp;rsquo;t display behaviour consistent with that message.
From my observations this happened because the role of the trainers was defined as &amp;lsquo;senior team member&amp;rsquo; which meant that if a trainer saw something going wrong they&amp;rsquo;d try and fix it since that&amp;rsquo;s what they&amp;rsquo;d do in a normal team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Similarities with &#39;Discussing the Undiscussable&#39;</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/09/thoughtworks-university-similarities-with-discussing-the-undiscussable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 10:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/09/thoughtworks-university-similarities-with-discussing-the-undiscussable/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading the final chapter of William Noonan&amp;rsquo;s Discussing the Undiscussable titled &amp;lsquo;Helping Those Who Teach, Learn&amp;rsquo; and a couple of the ideas that he describes seem quite applicable to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing at ThoughtWorks University.
Modelling the skills When teaching the Mutual Learning Model Noonan suggests that the practitioner needs to be able to produce actions consistent with the model in real time situations rather than just being able to do convincing presentations on the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Letting people explore</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/06/thoughtworks-university-letting-people-explore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/06/thoughtworks-university-letting-people-explore/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been acting as the tech lead on the project that we&amp;rsquo;re working on at ThoughtWorks University and as a result I sometimes find myself being dragged away from my pair to help someone else.
An interesting thing which I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed on more than one occasion is that when I&amp;rsquo;ve come back from helping - maybe 15 or 20 minutes later - my pair has actually got much further than I expected them to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: The coaching/training conflict</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/03/thoughtworks-university-the-coachingtraining-conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 17:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/04/03/thoughtworks-university-the-coachingtraining-conflict/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in an earlier post Sumeet has been encouraging us to act more as coaches rather than trainers during ThoughtWorks University but it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as easy as it seems.
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that there are a few things that contribute to this difficulty.
Assessment The biggest obstacle is that by the end of TWU the trainers are required to send a review about each of the grads to the respective Resource Managers describing each person&amp;rsquo;s current level of skill in various categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: The use of games</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/30/thoughtworks-university-the-use-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/30/thoughtworks-university-the-use-of-games/</guid>
      <description>When I attended ThoughtWorks University in August 2006 we spent quite a bit of time playing games which had been designed to help us to achieve various learning objectives.
At the time I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much about it but now being on the other side as a trainer I&amp;rsquo;ve started to doubt whether these types of sessions are as useful as I originally thought.
I recently came across a blog post Sumeet wrote last year where he talks about effective e-learning environments and I think his point still applies here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: A double loop learning example</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/30/thoughtworks-university-a-double-loop-learning-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 19:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/30/thoughtworks-university-a-double-loop-learning-example/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about recently is the idea of single and double loop learning which were defined by Chris Argyris and Donald Schon in their book &amp;lsquo;Organizational Learning: A theory of action perspective&amp;rsquo; in 1978.
 I quite like the definitions that Mark Smith gives for these types of learning in his article about Chris Argyris:
Single Loop Learning  Single-loop learning seems to be present when goals, values, frameworks and, to a significant extent, strategies are taken for granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Pulling the &#39;pearls&#39;</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/29/thoughtworks-university-pulling-the-pearls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 18:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/29/thoughtworks-university-pulling-the-pearls/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about the coding dojo style week that we ran at ThoughtWorks University last week and I briefly mentioned that we used break out sessions to cover topics (&amp;lsquo;the pearls&amp;rsquo;) that people didn&amp;rsquo;t totally understand.
To describe that in more detail what we did to start with was write the name of each of the 90&amp;frasl;180 minute sessions on a card and put it on the wall under a &amp;lsquo;To Do&amp;rsquo; heading:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Coding Dojo Style</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/29/thoughtworks-university-coding-dojo-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 17:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/29/thoughtworks-university-coding-dojo-style/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that Sumeet has been encouraging at ThoughtWorks University is the idea that the &amp;lsquo;trainers&amp;rsquo; should be in a coaching role rather than a training one.
As a result of this suggestion one of the things we&amp;rsquo;ve done is to change the style of the second week so that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t full of sessions/workshops but instead involved working on code as a group.
Jim came up with the idea of the &amp;lsquo;exploded story&amp;rsquo; whereby we spent the whole of last week as a group working on one story for Sukrupa while spending quite a bit of time exploring the different activities that playing a story end to end would involve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Brain dumping</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/23/twu-brain-dumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 18:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/23/twu-brain-dumping/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that I&amp;rsquo;m learning while working at ThoughtWorks University is to bite my tongue a bit to allow people to learn in their own way.
I noticed this particularly yesterday in a refactoring session we were doing.
For about 10-15 minutes in the middle of the session we&amp;rsquo;d managed to get the code into a state where it didn&amp;rsquo;t compile and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t run the tests.
The &amp;lsquo;natural&amp;rsquo; inclination in that situation for me would be to step in and impart some &amp;lsquo;wisdom&amp;rsquo; about the importance of taking small steps while refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: A refactoring dojo</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/22/thoughtworks-university-a-refactoring-dojo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 19:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/22/thoughtworks-university-a-refactoring-dojo/</guid>
      <description>I facilitated a refactoring session today at ThoughtWorks University where we spent the morning refactoring our way through one of the problems the grads had to work on as part of the pre coursework.
The previous version of this session has been more structured, whereby one of the trainers worked solo at the keyboard and took suggestions from the group about which refactoring to cover next.
There are a certain number of refactorings that the session aims to introduce and the trainer would have practiced beforehand so they could make these fairly flawlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Presenting</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/17/pair-presenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 06:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/17/pair-presenting/</guid>
      <description>Over the last year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve had some opportunities to pair with a few different people on sessions/presentations that we&amp;rsquo;ve been giving.
I much prefer doing this than presenting something by myself mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s much more fun and seems to encourage more participation than when I do something alone.
I feel that it&amp;rsquo;s probably easier to pair present if you both have similar opinions on the subject matter and are comfortable with a similar style of delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWU: Fishbowl</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/15/twu-fishbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 01:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/15/twu-fishbowl/</guid>
      <description>As part of a session on ThoughtWorks values at ThoughtWorks Univesity we held a fishbowl to discuss the trade offs we often have to make between the values when confronted with real life situations.
 A fishbowl conversation is a form of dialog that can be used when discussing topics within large groups. Four to five chairs are arranged in an inner circle. This is the fishbowl. The remaining chairs are arranged outside the fishbowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWU: Session Preparation - Limited WIP</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/09/twu-session-preparation-limited-wip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 14:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/09/twu-session-preparation-limited-wip/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a fair percentage of the last couple of weeks preparing sessions for ThoughtWorks University and one thing Frankie has been trying to encourage is only preparing one at a time i.e. limited work in progress
Normally I&amp;rsquo;d be completely in favour of that approach but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work at all for me with this type of work.
There seem to be a few parts to creating a session, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWU: Session Design - Measurable goals</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/04/twu-session-design-measurable-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 02:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/03/04/twu-session-design-measurable-goals/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been spending our time recently preparing the sessions for the next ThoughtWorks University batch and one thing Sumeet has encouraged us to do is ensure that we have a measurable goal for each session.
In our case that means that we need to design our sessions with the intention of the grads being able to do something rather than understand something after the session.
It&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to measure whether someone understands something and from what I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed having a goal of someone understanding something can encourage you to put in more than is strictly necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThoughtWorks University: Balancing helping and learning</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/02/19/thoughtworks-university-balancing-helping-and-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 15:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/02/19/thoughtworks-university-balancing-helping-and-learning/</guid>
      <description>6 months after my first attempt to train one of the ThoughtWorks University batches was cut short I&amp;rsquo;m back in Bangalore again and spent the first few days of this week pairing with the grads.
It&amp;rsquo;s been interesting for me trying to balance how much I help and suggest ideas while still allowing them to learn at the same time.
At the moment I think I&amp;rsquo;m leaning too far towards helping and not realising until later on that my colleague hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite understood why I&amp;rsquo;d suggested what I did and therefore hadn&amp;rsquo;t learnt anything from my suggestion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One idea at a time</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/08/12/one-idea-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 18:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/08/12/one-idea-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>One thing I noticed while pairing with some of the ThoughtWorks University guys a few weeks ago is that I had an almost overwhelming urge to show them all sorts of coding techniques that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, probably to the point where it&amp;rsquo;d be more confusing than helpful.
JK pointed out that it&amp;rsquo;s more effective to bite your tongue and just focus on one idea at a time which is something that the authors of Agile Coaching touch on briefly at the beginning of the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning and Situated cognition</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/08/10/learning-and-situated-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 03:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/08/10/learning-and-situated-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Sumeet recently blogged about the new style ThoughtWorks University that he and the other trainers have introduced and although I only got to see it in action for a few days it seemed clear to me that it was an improvement on the original version.
The questions being asked, discussions being had and situations that were coming up were pretty much the same as I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on any software project that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prepared mind vs having context when learning new ideas</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/07/22/the-prepared-mind-vs-having-context-when-learning-new-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 04:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2010/07/22/the-prepared-mind-vs-having-context-when-learning-new-ideas/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a trainer for ThoughtWorks University (TWU) and the participants have some Industrial Logic e-learning material to work through before they take part in the 6 week training program.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through the refactoring/code smells courses myself and while I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding it really useful, I think this was partly because I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to link the material to situations that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in code bases that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on over the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>