<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brexit on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/brexit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in brexit on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/brexit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing Brexit: Did the threat work?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/27/graphing-brexit-did-the-threat-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/27/graphing-brexit-did-the-threat-work/</guid>
      <description>Following on from the blog post where we compared how MPs and parties voted on Brexit indicative measures, in this post we&amp;#8217;re going to explore how Conservative MPs have voted with respect to a no deal exit from the European Union. In particular we&amp;#8217;d like to know whether the threat to have the party whip removed had an impact on how they voted in the recent motion to request an extension to work out a deal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing Brexit: MPs vs Parties</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/23/graphing-brexit-mps-vs-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/23/graphing-brexit-mps-vs-parties/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post of the Graphing Brexit series we computed the average vote by party. In this post we&amp;#8217;re going to take those average party scores and compare them against the votes placed by individual MPs. The goal is to determine whether, Brexit wise, MPs are representing the right party!
 It won&amp;#8217;t be perfect since we know that not everyone in a party voted the same way, but it should still give us some fun results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing Brexit: Plotting how the parties voted</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/20/graphing-brexit-charting-how-the-parties-voted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/09/20/graphing-brexit-charting-how-the-parties-voted/</guid>
      <description>Over the last week I&amp;#8217;ve revisited the Brexit Graph that I created in March 2019, this time looking at how the parties voted on average on each of the indicative votes.
 To recap, we have a graph that has the following schema:
   Since the initial post I&amp;#8217;ve slightly changed how the MEMBER_OF relationship works. As several MPs have switched MPs in the intervening months, we&amp;#8217;re now storing a start property to indicate when they started representing a party and an end property to indicate when they stopped representing a party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding famous MPs based on their Wikipedia Page Views</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/04/01/famous-mps-wikipedia-pageviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2019/04/01/famous-mps-wikipedia-pageviews/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Graphing Brexit series of blog posts, I wanted to work out who were the most important Members of the UK parliament, and after a bit of Googling I realised that views of their Wikipedia pages would do the trick.
 I initially found my way to tools.wmflabs.org, which is great for exploring the popularity of an individual MP, but not so good if you want to extract the data for 600 of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>