<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>streamlit on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/streamlit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in streamlit on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/tag/streamlit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Head to Head with DuckDB and Streamlit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2023/03/31/tennis-head-to-head-duckdb-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2023/03/31/tennis-head-to-head-duckdb-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we’re going to learn how to build an application to compare the matches between two ATP tennis players. DuckDB and Streamlit will be our partners in crime for this mission.
Set up To get started, let’s create a virtual environment:
python -m venv .venv source .venv/bin/activate And now install some libraries:
pip install duckdb streamlit streamlit-searchbox And now let’s open a file, app.py and import the packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlit: Overwrite previous value in a loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2022/02/19/streamlit-overwrite-previous-value-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2022/02/19/streamlit-overwrite-previous-value-loop/</guid>
      <description>I was recently building a Streamlit app in which I was looping through a stream of values and wanted to only print out the most recent value. In this blog post we’ll learn how to do that.
Figure 1. Streamlit: Overwrite previous value in a loop Setup If you want to play along you’ll need to create a virtual environment and install Streamlit:
python -m venv env source venv/bin/activate pip install streamlit Streamlit App Now, create a file app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlit: multiselect - AttributeError: &#39;numpy.ndarray&#39; object has no attribute &#39;index&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2020/03/31/streamlit-multiselect-numpy-no-attribute-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2020/03/31/streamlit-multiselect-numpy-no-attribute-index/</guid>
      <description>In this post we’ll learn how to overcome a problem I encountered while building a small Streamlit application to analyse John Hopkin’s data on the COVID-19 disease. The examples in this post use a CSV file that contains time series data of deaths in each country.
I started with the following code to create a multiselect widget that lists all countries and selected the United Kingdom by default:
import streamlit as st import pandas as pd default_countries = [&amp;#34;United Kingdom&amp;#34;] url=&amp;#34;https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Interactive UK Official Charts Data App with Streamlit and Neo4j</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/2020/01/16/interactive-uk-charts-quickgraph-neo4j-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/2020/01/16/interactive-uk-charts-quickgraph-neo4j-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across Streamlit, a tool that makes it easy to build data based single page web applications. I wanted to give it a try, and the UK Charts QuickGraph that I recently wrote about seemed like a good opportunity for that.
This blog post starts from where we left off. The data is loaded into Neo4j and we’ve written some queries to explore different aspects of the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
