<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strava on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/strava/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strava on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 05:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/strava/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo4j APOC: Importing data from Strava&#39;s paginated JSON API</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/06/05/neo4j-apoc-loading-data-strava-paginated-json-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 05:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/06/05/neo4j-apoc-loading-data-strava-paginated-json-api/</guid>
      <description>Over the weekend I&amp;#8217;ve been playing around with loading data from the Strava API into Neo4j and I started with the following Python script which creates a node with a Run label for each of my activities.
 If you want to follow along on your own data you&amp;#8217;ll need to get an API key via the &#39;My API Application&#39; section of the website. Once you&amp;#8217;ve got that put it in the TOKEN environment variable and you should be good to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava: Calculating the similarity of two runs</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/01/18/strava-calculating-similarity-two-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 23:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2018/01/18/strava-calculating-similarity-two-runs/</guid>
      <description>I go running several times a week and wanted to compare my runs against each other to see how similar they are.  I record my runs with the Strava app and it has an API that returns lat/long coordinates for each run in the Google encoded polyline algorithm format.  We can use the polyline library to decode these values into a list of lat/long tuples. For example: import polyline polyline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading and analysing Strava runs using PostgreSQL JSON data type</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2017/05/01/loading-and-analysing-strava-runs-using-postgresql-json-data-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 19:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2017/05/01/loading-and-analysing-strava-runs-using-postgresql-json-data-type/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I showed how to map Strava runs using data that I&#39;d extracted from their /activities API, but the API returns a lot of other data that I discarded because I wasn&#39;t sure what I should keep.  The API returns a nested JSON structure so the easiest solution would be to save each run as an individual file but I&#39;ve always wanted to try out PostgreSQL&#39;s JSON data type and this seemed like a good opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet: Mapping Strava runs/polylines on Open Street Map</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2017/04/29/leaflet-strava-polylines-osm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2017/04/29/leaflet-strava-polylines-osm/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a big Strava user and spent a bit of time last weekend playing around with their API to work out how to map all my runs.  Strava API and polylines  This is a two step process:   Call the /athlete/activities/ endpoint to get a list of all my activities For each of those activities call /activities/[activityId] endpoint to get more detailed information for each activity   That second API returns a &#39;polyline&#39; property which the documentation describes as follows:  Activity and segment API requests may include summary polylines of their respective routes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>