<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell
The Review I came across this book following recommendations by Jason Yip and Steven &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; List on Twitter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously read The Tipping Point and Blink and I like his easy going style so it was a no brainer that I was going to read this one.
I found that this book complimented Talent is Overrated quite nicely. Outliers covers how the story of how people became the best at what they do whereas Talent is Overrated focuses more on what you need to do if you want to become one of these people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does generalising specialist mean you can&#39;t be the best?</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/does-generalising-specialist-mean-you-cant-be-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 05:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/does-generalising-specialist-mean-you-cant-be-the-best/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s often said that people who are really good at what they do are so good at it because they have narrowed their focus in their area of specialty until they are only doing the thing that they are good at.
To use a football analogy, Manchester United&amp;rsquo;s Cristiano Ronaldo - widely acknowledged as the best footballer in the world at the moment - is absolutely brilliant when he has the ball at his feet, taking on defenders, getting in shots around the opposition penalty area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>