<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughtworks Anthology on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/tag/thoughtworks-anthology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughtworks Anthology on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 22:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/blog/tag/thoughtworks-anthology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Dojo #2: Bowling Game &amp; Object Calisthenics Continued</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2008/11/13/coding-dojo-2-bowling-game-object-calisthenics-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 22:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2008/11/13/coding-dojo-2-bowling-game-object-calisthenics-continued/</guid>
      <description>We ran another Coding Dojo on Wednesday night as part of ThoughtWorks Geek Night where we continued working on the Bowling Game problem from last week, keeping the Object Calisthenics approach broadly in mind but not sticking to it as strictly.
The Format This time we followed the Randori approach, with a projector beaming the code onto the wall, 2 people pairing on the problem and everyone else watching.
We rotated one of the pair every 7 minutes using the Minutes OS X widget to keep track of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Calisthenics: First thoughts</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2008/11/06/object-calisthenics-first-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 21:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2008/11/06/object-calisthenics-first-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>We ran an Object Calisthenics variation of Coding Dojo on Wednesday night as part of ThoughtWorks Geek Night in Sydney.
Object Calisthenics is an idea suggest by Jeff Bay in The ThoughtWorks Anthology , and lists 9 rules to writing better Object Oriented code. For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the book, the 9 rules are:
 Use only one level of indentation per method  Don&#39;t use the else keyword Wrap all primitives and strings Use only one dot per line Don&#39;t abbreviate Keep all entities small Don&#39;t use any classes with more than two instance variables Use first-class collections Don&#39;t use any getters/setters/properties  We decided to try and solve the Bowling Game Problem while applying these rules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>