<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hibernate on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/hibernate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hibernate on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 23:24:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/hibernate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Hibernate mappings: Setting up test data</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/30/testing-hibernate-mappings-setting-up-test-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 23:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/30/testing-hibernate-mappings-setting-up-test-data/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with my mini Hibernate mappings series, this post talks about the different ways of setting up the test datafor our Hibernate tests.
There are a couple of ways that we can setup data for Hibernate tests.
The benefit of this approach is that our test is pretty clean. It looks like any old unit test where we create an object and then check that what we get back is the same object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Hibernate mappings: Testing Equality</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/29/testing-hibernate-mappings-testing-equality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 18:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/29/testing-hibernate-mappings-testing-equality/</guid>
      <description>I started a mini Hibernate series with my last postwhere I spoke of there being three main areas to think about when it comes to testing:
Once we have worked out where to test the mappings from, if we have decided to test them through either our repository tests or directly from the Hibernate session then we have some choices to make around how to test for equality.
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this done in several ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Hibernate mappings: Where to test from?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/27/testing-hibernate-mappings-where-to-test-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/27/testing-hibernate-mappings-where-to-test-from/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to work with Hibernateand it&amp;rsquo;s .NET twin NHibernateon several of my projects and one of the more interesting decisions around its use is working out the best way to test the hibernate mappings that hook together our domain model and the database.
There are three decisions to make around how best to do this:
This post will focus on the ways I have seen with regards to choosing where to test the mappings from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>