<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plotly on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/plotly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plotly on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/tag/plotly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clustering YouTube comments using Ollama Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/27/clustering-youtube-comments-ollama-embeddings-nomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2024/02/27/clustering-youtube-comments-ollama-embeddings-nomic/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite tools in the LLM space is Ollama and if you want to learn how to use it, there’s no better place than Matt Williams&amp;#39; YouTube channel. His videos get a lot of comments and they tend to contain a treasure trove of the things that people are thinking about and the questions that they have. Matt recently did a video about embeddings in Ollama and I thought it’d be fun to try to get a high-level overview of what’s happening in the comments section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotly: Visualising a normal distribution given average and standard deviation</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/07/19/plotly-normal-distribution-average-stdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 04:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2023/07/19/plotly-normal-distribution-average-stdev/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing around with Microsoft’s TrueSkill algorithm, which attempts to quantify the skill of a player using the Bayesian inference algorithm. A rating in this system is a Gaussian distribution that starts with an average of 25 and a confidence of 8.333. I wanted to visualise various ratings using Plotly and that’s what we’ll be doing in this blog post.
To save you from having to install TrueSkill, we’re going to create a named tuple to simulate a TrueSkill Rating object:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dash: Configurable dcc.Interval</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/04/23/dash-configurable-dcc-interval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 02:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2022/04/23/dash-configurable-dcc-interval/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my blog post about building a Real-Time Crypto Dashboard, I’ve recently been working with the Dash low-code framework for building interactive data apps.
I was using the dcc.Interval component to automatically refresh components on the page and wanted to make the refresh interval configurable. In this blog post we’ll learn how to do that.
Figure 1. Dash: Configurable dcc.Interval Setup Let’s first setup our Python environment:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
