<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Review on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Review on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Badass: Making users awesome - Kathy Sierra: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I started reading Kathy Sierra&#39;s new book &#39;Badass: Making users awesome&#39; a couple of weeks ago and with the gift of flights to/from Stockholm this week I&#39;ve got through the rest of it.  I really enjoyed the book and have found myself returning to it almost every day to check up exactly what was said on a particular topic.  There were a few things that I&#39;ve taken away and have been going on about to anyone who will listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Thing About Hard Things - Ben Horowitz: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 23:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I came across &#39;The Hard Thing About Hard Things&#39; while reading an article about Ben Horowitz&#39;s venture capital firm and it was intriguing enough that I bought it and then read through it over a couple of days.
Although the blurb suggests that it&#39;s a book about about building and running a startup I think a lot of the lessons are applicable for any business.
These were some of the main points that stood out for me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming in Java - Venkat Subramaniam: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/03/23/functional-programming-in-java-venkat-subramaniam-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 21:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/03/23/functional-programming-in-java-venkat-subramaniam-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I picked up Venkat Subramaniam&#39;s &#39;Functional Programming in Java: Harnessing the Power of Java 8 Lambda Expressions&#39; to learn a little bit more about Java 8 having struggled to find any online tutorials which did that.
A big chunk of the book focuses on lambdas, functional collection parameters and lazy evaluation which will be familiar to users of C#, Clojure, Scala, Haskell, Ruby, Python, F# or libraries like totallylazy and Guava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Fast and Slow - Daniel Kahneman: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 22:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I picked up Daniel Kahneman&#39;s &#39;Thinking Fast and Slow&#39; after a recommendation by Mike Jones in early 2013 - it&#39;s taken me quite a while to get through it.
The book starts by describing our two styles of thinking...
 System 1 – operates automatically and quickly, with little or no effort and no sense of voluntary control.  System 2 – allocates attention to the effortful mental activities that demand it, including complex computations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well - William Zinsser: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 22:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I first came across William Zinsser&#39;s &#39;On Writing Well&#39; about a year ago, but put it down having flicked through a couple of the chapters that I felt were relevant.
It came back onto my radar a month ago and this time I decided to read it cover to cover as I was sure there were some insights that I&#39;d missed due to my haphazard approach the first time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 algorithms that changed the future - John MacCormick: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book 9 algorithms that changed the future (the ingenious ideas that drive today&#39;s computers) by John MacCormick
My Thoughts I came across this book while idly browsing a book store and since I&#39;ve found most introduction to algorithms books very dry I thought it&#39;d be interesting to see what one aimed at the general public would be like.
Overall it was an enjoyable read and I quite like the pattern that the author used for each algorithm, which was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Signal and the Noise - Nate Silver</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</guid>
      <description>Nate Silver is famous for having correctly predicted the winner of all 50 states in the 2012 United States elections and Sid recommended his book so I could learn more about statistics for the A/B tests that we were running.
I thought the book was a really good introduction to applied statistics and by using real life examples which most people would be able to relate to it makes a potentially dull subject interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Retrospective Handbook - Pat Kua</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 21:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Pat Kua recently published a book he&amp;rsquo;s been working on for the first half of the year titled &amp;lsquo;The Retrospective Handbook&amp;rsquo; - a book in which Pat shares his experiences with retrospectives and gives advice to budding facilitators.
I was intrigued what the book would be like because the skill gap between Pat and me with respect to facilitating retrospectives is huge and I&amp;rsquo;ve often found that experts in a subject can have a tendency to be a bit preachy when writing about their subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 21:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d heard about The Lean Startup for a long time before I actually read it, mainly from following the &amp;lsquo;Startup Lessons Learned&amp;rsquo; blog, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the book until a colleague suggested a meetup to discuss how we might apply the ideas on our projects.
My general learning from the book is that we need to take the idea of creating tight feedback loops, which we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt in the agile/lean worlds, and apply it to product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Undiscussable: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I came across the work of Chris Argyris at the start of the year and in a twitter conversation with Benjamin Mitchell he suggested that Bill Noonan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Discussing the Undiscussable&amp;rsquo; was the most accessible text for someone new to the subject.
In the book Noonan runs through a series of different tools that Chris Argyris originally came up with for helping people to handle difficult conversational situations more effectively.
I really like the way the book is written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures of Johnny Bunko -  The Last Career Guide You&#39;ll Ever Need: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 17:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I read Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s A Whole New Mind earlier in the year but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of The Adventures of Johnny Bunko until my colleague Sumeet Moghe mentioned it in a conversation during ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s XConf, an internal conference run here.
The book is written in the Manga format so it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly quick to read and it gives 6 ideas around building a career.
I&amp;rsquo;m generally not a fan of the idea of &amp;lsquo;building a career&amp;rsquo; - generally when I hear that phrase it involves having a &amp;lsquo;five year&amp;rsquo; plan and other such concepts which I consider to be pointless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linchpin: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 16:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a couple of Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s other books - Tribes and The Dip - and found them fairly readable so I figured his latest offering, Linchpin, would probably be worth a read too.
This is the first book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the iPad&amp;rsquo;s Kindle application and it was a reasonably good reading experience - I particularly like the fact that you can make notes and highlight certain parts of the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maverick: Book review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 07:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>My colleagues Frankie and Danilo have been recommending &amp;lsquo;Maverick&amp;rsquo; to me for a long time and I finally got around to reading it.
In this book Ricardo Semler, the CEO of Semco, tells the story of the company and how he helped evolved the organisation into one which is more employee led and embraces ideas such as open &amp;amp; self set salaries while encouraging civil obedience in the workforce as a necessity to alert the organisation to its problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting real: Book review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 21:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across 37 Signals &amp;lsquo;Getting Real&amp;rsquo; book where they go through their approach to building web applications and there have certainly been some good reminders and ideas on the best way to do this.
These are some of my favourite parts:
 Ship it!  If there are minor bugs, ship it as soon you have the core scenarios nailed and ship the bug ﬁxes to web gradually after that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Lecture - Randy Pausch</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 14:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Last Lecture: Achieving Your Childhood Dreams&amp;rsquo; and read the corresponding book and although it&amp;rsquo;s not directly related to software development I think that some of the points that he makes are really intriguing.
These were some of the parts that particularly stood out for me:
 Introduce the elephant in the room - whatever it is that people are really thinking about, put it out in the open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug It: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 05:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</guid>
      <description>David Agans&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; is the best debugging book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so I was intrigued to see that there was another book being written on the subject.
Paul Butcher offered me a copy of the book to review so I was keen to see whether it was more like &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Release It&amp;rsquo; as Ted Neward suggests.
The Book Debug It by Paul Butcher
The Review Much like Krzysztof Kozmic I found that a lot of the ideas early on in the book were similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught by my ThoughtWorks colleagues over the last 3 1&amp;frasl;2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UML: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite recent blog posts is one written by Sammy Larbi on coupling and cohesion and while discussing it with Phil he suggested that I would probably like this book and in particular the chapter on connascence which I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written about.
The Book Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UML by Meilir Page-Jones
The Review I really enjoyed reading this book and I think it&amp;rsquo;s one that I could come back and read again to gain something else from in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real World Functional Programming: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Real World Functional Programming by Tomas Petricek with Jon Skeet (corresponding website)
The Review I decided to read this book after being somewhat inspired to learn more about functional programming after talking with Phil about his experiences learning Clojure. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a .NET project so it seemed to make sense that F# was the language I picked to learn.
What did I learn?  I&#39;ve worked with C# 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent is Overrated: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 20:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Talent is Overrated by Geoff Colvin
The Review I came across this book on Jason Yip&amp;rsquo;s Twitter feed while the idea of 10,000 hours to become an expert at any given skill was being discussed. I&amp;rsquo;m reading Outliers as well and the two books seem to complement each other quite well.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in how we can apply deliberate practice in software development, perhaps using the medium of coding dojos, to become better developers in a more effective manner than just normal practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiichi Ohno&#39;s Workplace Management: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 00:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Taiichi Ohno&amp;rsquo;s Workplace Management by Taiichi Ohno
The Review Having completed The Toyota Way a few weeks ago I was speaking with Jason about what books were good to read next - he recommended this one and The Toyota Way Fieldbook.
I struggled to see a connection to software development with a lot of what I read, but there were certainly words of wisdom that we can apply to continuously improve our ability to deliver projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Learning and Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 02:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Pragmatic Learning and Thinking by Andy Hunt
The Review I came across this book when reading a post linking lean to the Dreyfus Model on Dan North&amp;rsquo;s blog.
I have a keen interest in theories of learning and have completed an NLP Practitioner&amp;rsquo;s course so the ideas described in the book summary immediately appealed to me.
After coming across the concept of Reading Deliberately in Chapter 6 of the book I decided I should give the SQ3Q approach to reading books its first run out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>