<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>altdotnet on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/altdotnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in altdotnet on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 22:09:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/altdotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt.NET Sydney User Group Meeting #1</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/01/altnet-sydney-user-group-meeting-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 22:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/01/altnet-sydney-user-group-meeting-1/</guid>
      <description>James Crisp and Richard Banks arranged the first Alt.NET Sydney User Group meeting held on Tuesday night at the ThoughtWorks office.
 The first thing to say is thanks to James and Richard for getting this setup so quickly - it was less than a month ago that Richard suggested the idea of creating a group on the Alt.NET mailing list.
 Richard and James have already written summaries of what went on but I thought I&amp;#8217;d give some of my thoughts as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt.NET UK Conference 2.0</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/14/altnet-uk-conference-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 16:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/14/altnet-uk-conference-20/</guid>
      <description>I spent most of yesterday at the 2nd Alt.NET UK conference at Conway Hall in London.
 First of all kudos to Ian Cooper, Alan Dean and Ben Hall for arranging it. There seemed to be a lot more people around than for the one in February which no doubt took a lot of arranging.
 It was again run using the open spaces format and we started with an interesting discussion on what Alt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 01:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve had the opportunity to have worked with many different people pair programming wise over the last year or so, and having seen it done in several different ways thought it would be interesting to work through some of my thoughts about this Extreme Programming (XP) originated practice.
 First of all it seems to me that pair programming is a technique that is used with a lot more frequency at ThoughtWorks than at any other IT organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>