<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://mneedham.github.io/tag/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 23:07:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mneedham.github.io/tag/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure/Emacs/nrepl: Stacktrace-less error messages</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2013/09/22/clojureemacsnrepl-stacktrace-less-error-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 23:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2013/09/22/clojureemacsnrepl-stacktrace-less-error-messages/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started using the Emacs + nrepl combination to play around with Clojure I&#39;ve been getting fairly non descript error messages whenever I pass the wrong parameters to a function.
For example if I try to update a non existent key in a form I get a Null Pointer Exception:
&amp;gt; (update-in {} [:mark] inc) NullPointerException clojure.lang.Numbers.ops (Numbers.java:942)  In this case it&#39;s clear that the hash doesn&#39;t have a key &#39;:mark&#39; so the function blows up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs/Clojure: Starting out with paredit</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2012/10/31/emacsclojure-starting-out-with-paredit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 08:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2012/10/31/emacsclojure-starting-out-with-paredit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been complaining recently to Jen and Bruce about the lack of a beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to emacs paredit mode which seems to be the defacto approach for people working with Clojure and both pointed me to the paredit cheat sheet.
While it&amp;rsquo;s very comprehensive, I found that it&amp;rsquo;s a little overwhelming for a complete newbie like myself.
I therefore thought it&amp;rsquo;d be useful to write a bit about a couple of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up from pairing with Jen on little bits of Clojure over the last couple of months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs: Re-mapping the Control and Meta Keys on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/07/17/emacs-re-mapping-the-control-and-meta-keys-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 10:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mneedham.github.io/2011/07/17/emacs-re-mapping-the-control-and-meta-keys-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve started playing around with Clojure again I thought it&amp;rsquo;d make sense to use emacs as my editor and therefore needed to work out how to remap the Ctrl and Meta to keys which are more accessible on the MBP&amp;rsquo;s keyboard.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I like using the Caps Lock for Ctrl and that&amp;rsquo;s reasonably easy to change by navigating to &amp;lsquo;System Preferences &amp;gt; Keyboard &amp;gt; Modifier Keys&amp;rsquo;:
 The Meta key is Escape by default and I wanted to map it to the right Command key as that&amp;rsquo;s much easier for me to get to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>