<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucene on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/tag/lucene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lucene on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 09:53:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/blog/tag/lucene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>neo4j/cypher/Lucene: Dealing with special characters</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/neo4jcypherlucene-dealing-with-special-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 09:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/neo4jcypherlucene-dealing-with-special-characters/</guid>
      <description>neo4j uses Lucene to handle indexing of nodes and relationships in the graph but something that can be a bit confusing at first is how to handle special characters in Lucene queries.
For example let&#39;s say we set up a database with the following data:
CREATE ({name: &amp;quot;-one&amp;quot;}) CREATE ({name: &amp;quot;-two&amp;quot;}) CREATE ({name: &amp;quot;-three&amp;quot;}) CREATE ({name: &amp;quot;four&amp;quot;})  And for whatever reason we only wanted to return the nodes that begin with a hyphen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neo4j/cypher: Playing around with time</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/neo4jcypher-playing-around-with-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2013/03/31/neo4jcypher-playing-around-with-time/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve done a bit of modelling with years and months in neo4j graphs that I&#39;ve worked on previously but I haven&#39;t ever done anything with time so I thought it&#39;d be interesting to have a go with my football graph.
I came across this StackOverflow post on my travels which suggested that indexing nodes by time would be helpful and since I have a bunch of football matches with associated times I thought I&#39;d try it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>neography/neo4j/Lucene: Getting a list of all the nodes indexed</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2012/04/17/neographyneo4jlucene-getting-a-list-of-all-the-nodes-indexed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 06:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/blog/2012/04/17/neographyneo4jlucene-getting-a-list-of-all-the-nodes-indexed/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with neo4j using the neography gem to create a graph of all the people in ThoughtWorks and the connections between them based on working with each other.
I created a UI where you could type in the names of two people and see when they&amp;rsquo;ve worked together or the path between the shortest path between them if they haven&amp;rsquo;t.
I thought it would be cool to have auto complete functionality when typing in a name but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to partially query the index of people&amp;rsquo;s names that I&amp;rsquo;d created.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>