<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communcation on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://mneedham.github.io/tag/communcation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communcation on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 22:16:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mneedham.github.io/tag/communcation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations; Tell a story</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2012/08/14/presentations-tell-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 22:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2012/08/14/presentations-tell-a-story/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago before an F# talk that I gave at the .NET user group in Sydney my colleague Erik Doernenburg gave me some advice about how I should structure the talk.
(paraphrasing)  He suggested that in a lot of talks he&amp;rsquo;d seen the presenter rattle off a bunch of information about a topic but hadn&amp;rsquo;t provided any insight into their own experience with the topic.
If two people give a talk on the same topic they therefore end up being fairly similar talks even though each person may have a totally different perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Nic&#39;s &#39;How to stop killing people with your public speeches&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mneedham.github.io/2011/11/16/dr-nics-how-to-stop-killing-people-with-your-public-speeches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 22:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mneedham.github.io/2011/11/16/dr-nics-how-to-stop-killing-people-with-your-public-speeches/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a really cool blog post by Dr Nic titled &amp;lsquo;How to stop killing people with your public speeches&amp;rsquo; where he talks about the importance of practicing our presentations so that they actually make an impact on our audience.
Towards the end of the post he suggests joining Toastmasters as a useful first step for getting used to speaking to a group of people and as an added bonus you get feedback after each speech you give.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>