<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qtb on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/qtb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qtb on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 23:51:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/qtb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: thetrainline.com - &#39;Scale at speed&#39;</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/29/qtb-thetrainline-com-scale-at-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 23:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/29/qtb-thetrainline-com-scale-at-speed/</guid>
      <description>About 18 months on from the first ThoughtWorks QTB that I saw about offshoring, on Wednesday night I attended the latest QTB in Manchester titled &amp;lsquo;thetrainline.com - Scale at speed&amp;rsquo;.
The presenters were thetrainline.com&amp;rsquo;s CIO David Jack and the Managing Director of ThoughtWorks India, Mahesh Baxi.
They took us on the journey that thetrainline.com have taken while working with ThoughtWorks to re-architect part of their system to allow them to quickly deliver new functionality on the 2,500 websites that their portal technology powers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 23:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/10/01/qtb-agile-governance-managing-the-enterprise-issues/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch the latest ThoughtWorks Australia Quarterly Technology Briefing in Sydney on Wednesday where my colleague Lindy Stephens, Suncorp&amp;rsquo;s Josh Melville and Lonely Planet&amp;rsquo;s Nigel Dalton presented on &amp;lsquo;Agile Governance - Managing the Enterprise Issues&amp;rsquo;.
I was actually unsure of how interesting it would be to me as the title seemed a bit dull but it was actually quite entertaining and not at all what I expected.
These are some of the things I picked up from the presentation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 23:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/24/qtb-agile-adoption-how-to-stuff-it-up/</guid>
      <description>I attended the most recent ThoughtWorks Quarterly Technology briefing on Tuesday which was titled &amp;lsquo;Agile Adoption - How to stuff it up&amp;rsquo; and presented by my colleagues Andy Marks and Martin Fowler.
There seems to be quite a few books out at the moment about how to introduce a more agile approach into your organisation - I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Lean-Agile Software Development and Becoming Agile and there is also a book called Scaling Lean and Agile Development - so I was intrigued to see whether the messages from this talk would be similar to those in these books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QTB: Lean Times Require Lean Thinking</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/qtb-lean-times-require-lean-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/25/qtb-lean-times-require-lean-thinking/</guid>
      <description>I went to watch the latest ThoughtWorks Quarterly Technology Briefing on Tuesday, which was presented by my colleague Jason Yip and Paul Heaton, titled &amp;lsquo;Lean Times Require Lean Thinking&amp;lsquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading quite a bit of lean related material lately but I thought it would be interesting to hear about it directly from the perspective of two people who have been involved with applying the concepts in organisations.
What did I learn?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>