<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pairing on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/pairing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pairing on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 23:48:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/pairing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: The Over Eager Driver</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 23:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/pair-programming-the-over-eager-driver/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting situations that can arise when pair programming is that one person dominates the driving and their pair can hardly get a look in.
This is not necessarily because they are hogging the keyboard - it is often just the case that they are the stronger technically in the pair and the other person isn&amp;rsquo;t willing to ask for the keyboard.
A big part of the value in pair programming comes from having both people taking turns at driving and navigating from my experience and there are several ideas that I have come across for trying to encourage a more collaborative approach to pair programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Benefits of the pair switch mid story</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/04/pair-programming-benefits-of-the-pair-switch-mid-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/04/pair-programming-benefits-of-the-pair-switch-mid-story/</guid>
      <description>On my current project we&amp;rsquo;ve been having some discussions around the frequency with which we rotate pairs, the feeling being that we probably keep the same pairs for a bit too long.
We discussed using techniques such as promiscuous pairing, which takes the idea of pair rotation to an extreme, but have settled on making our rotations more or less daily.
One interesting thing I noticed from some recent pair switching was the immediate benefit we can realise from the pair rotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Driving quickly</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/02/pair-programming-driving-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 22:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/02/pair-programming-driving-quickly/</guid>
      <description>In order to experience the full benefits of pair programming it is important to try and reduce the chance of the navigator getting bored and losing focus.
One of the main ways that we can do this is by ensuring that we have a quick turnaround between the driver and navigator, and this can be done by ensuring that when we are driving we are doing so as quickly as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Pair Flow</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/17/pair-programming-pair-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 00:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/17/pair-programming-pair-flow/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post about Team Productivity I stumbled upon the idea that while pair programming there could be such a concept as pair flow.
The term &amp;lsquo;flow&amp;rsquo; is used to describe a situation where you are totally immersed in the work you&amp;rsquo;re doing and where time seems to go by without you even noticing.
This can also happen when pair programming and I think there are some factors which can make it more likely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Why would I pair on this?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/09/pair-programming-why-would-i-pair-on-this/</guid>
      <description>In the comments of my previous post on pairing Vivek made the following comment about when we should pair:
 The simplest principle I have is to use &#34;conscious&#34; pairing vs. &#34;unconscious&#34; pairing. A pair should always *know* why they are pairing.  On previous projects I have worked on there have been several tasks where it has been suggested that there is little value in pairing. I decided to try and apply Vivek&amp;rsquo;s principle of knowing why we might pair on these tasks to see if there is actually any value in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: What do we gain from it?</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 22:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/28/pair-programming-what-do-we-gain-from-it/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Vivek Vaid has an interesting post about parallel-paired programming where he talks about introducing lean concepts into deciding when we should pair to get maximum productivity.
Midway through the post he mentions that the original reason that we starting pairing was for &amp;lsquo;collaborative design&amp;rsquo; which got me thinking whether there are reasons beyond this why we would want to pair.
I have often worked on clients where the value of pair programming has been questioned and it has been suggested that we should only adhere to this practice for tasks where it adds most value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Junior/Junior pair</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 23:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/13/pair-programming-juniorjunior-pair/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to Pair Programming the Junior/Junior pairing is considered the most likely to lead to disaster. The old joke being that if you pair two Junior Developers together then you&amp;rsquo;d better hope you have a revert function on your repository. But is this fair?
Certainly pairing two Junior Developers together means that you automatically lose the value of the experience and mentoring skills that you would get if there was a Senior Developer as part of the pair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Pairing with a QA</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/pair-programming-pairing-with-a-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/08/11/pair-programming-pairing-with-a-qa/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about pair programming in some of my previous posts as I find the dynamic it creates quite intriguing.
One idea which was suggested around the time I wrote those posts by my project manager at the time was developers pairing with the QA or BA on certain tasks. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to experience it on that particular project but over the last week I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing quick a bit of build work and for some of that I was pairing with our QA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: The Non Driving Pair</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/14/pair-programming-the-non-driving-pair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 01:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/14/pair-programming-the-non-driving-pair/</guid>
      <description>One of the intriguing aspects of pair programming for me is that of the non driving person in the pair – what are they supposed to do?!
Obviously there are fairly well known strategies for more interactive pairing, such as Ping Pong and Ball and Board (which is where one person controls the mouse and the other the keyboard), but neither of these strategies suggest what to do when you are not driving</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 01:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/02/10/pair-programming-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had the opportunity to have worked with many different people pair programming wise over the last year or so, and having seen it done in several different ways thought it would be interesting to work through some of my thoughts about this Extreme Programming (XP) originated practice.
First of all it seems to me that pair programming is a technique that is used with a lot more frequency at ThoughtWorks than at any other IT organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>