<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Badass: Making users awesome - Kathy Sierra: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I started reading Kathy Sierra&#39;s new book &#39;Badass: Making users awesome&#39; a couple of weeks ago and with the gift of flights to/from Stockholm this week I&#39;ve got through the rest of it.  I really enjoyed the book and have found myself returning to it almost every day to check up exactly what was said on a particular topic.  There were a few things that I&#39;ve taken away and have been going on about to anyone who will listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Thing About Hard Things - Ben Horowitz: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 23:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I came across &#39;The Hard Thing About Hard Things&#39; while reading an article about Ben Horowitz&#39;s venture capital firm and it was intriguing enough that I bought it and then read through it over a couple of days.
Although the blurb suggests that it&#39;s a book about about building and running a startup I think a lot of the lessons are applicable for any business.
These were some of the main points that stood out for me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Fast and Slow - Daniel Kahneman: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 22:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I picked up Daniel Kahneman&#39;s &#39;Thinking Fast and Slow&#39; after a recommendation by Mike Jones in early 2013 - it&#39;s taken me quite a while to get through it.
The book starts by describing our two styles of thinking...
 System 1 – operates automatically and quickly, with little or no effort and no sense of voluntary control.  System 2 – allocates attention to the effortful mental activities that demand it, including complex computations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well - William Zinsser: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 22:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I first came across William Zinsser&#39;s &#39;On Writing Well&#39; about a year ago, but put it down having flicked through a couple of the chapters that I felt were relevant.
It came back onto my radar a month ago and this time I decided to read it cover to cover as I was sure there were some insights that I&#39;d missed due to my haphazard approach the first time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 algorithms that changed the future - John MacCormick: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book 9 algorithms that changed the future (the ingenious ideas that drive today&#39;s computers) by John MacCormick
My Thoughts I came across this book while idly browsing a book store and since I&#39;ve found most introduction to algorithms books very dry I thought it&#39;d be interesting to see what one aimed at the general public would be like.
Overall it was an enjoyable read and I quite like the pattern that the author used for each algorithm, which was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Signal and the Noise - Nate Silver</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</guid>
      <description>Nate Silver is famous for having correctly predicted the winner of all 50 states in the 2012 United States elections and Sid recommended his book so I could learn more about statistics for the A/B tests that we were running.
I thought the book was a really good introduction to applied statistics and by using real life examples which most people would be able to relate to it makes a potentially dull subject interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Retrospective Handbook - Pat Kua</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 21:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Pat Kua recently published a book he&amp;rsquo;s been working on for the first half of the year titled &amp;lsquo;The Retrospective Handbook&amp;rsquo; - a book in which Pat shares his experiences with retrospectives and gives advice to budding facilitators.
I was intrigued what the book would be like because the skill gap between Pat and me with respect to facilitating retrospectives is huge and I&amp;rsquo;ve often found that experts in a subject can have a tendency to be a bit preachy when writing about their subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 21:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d heard about The Lean Startup for a long time before I actually read it, mainly from following the &amp;lsquo;Startup Lessons Learned&amp;rsquo; blog, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the book until a colleague suggested a meetup to discuss how we might apply the ideas on our projects.
My general learning from the book is that we need to take the idea of creating tight feedback loops, which we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt in the agile/lean worlds, and apply it to product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Undiscussable: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I came across the work of Chris Argyris at the start of the year and in a twitter conversation with Benjamin Mitchell he suggested that Bill Noonan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Discussing the Undiscussable&amp;rsquo; was the most accessible text for someone new to the subject.
In the book Noonan runs through a series of different tools that Chris Argyris originally came up with for helping people to handle difficult conversational situations more effectively.
I really like the way the book is written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books: Know why you&#39;re reading it </title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/books-know-why-youre-reading-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 03:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/books-know-why-youre-reading-it/</guid>
      <description>Something which I frequently forget while reading books is that it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite useful to know exactly why you&amp;rsquo;re reading it i.e. what knowledge are you trying to gain by doing so.
I noticed this again recently while reading The Agile Samurai - it&amp;rsquo;s one of the books we ask ThoughtWorks University participants to read before they come to India.
Implicitly I knew that I just wanted to get a rough idea of what sort of things it&amp;rsquo;s telling people but I somewhat foolishly just started reading it cover to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures of Johnny Bunko -  The Last Career Guide You&#39;ll Ever Need: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 17:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I read Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s A Whole New Mind earlier in the year but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of The Adventures of Johnny Bunko until my colleague Sumeet Moghe mentioned it in a conversation during ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s XConf, an internal conference run here.
The book is written in the Manga format so it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly quick to read and it gives 6 ideas around building a career.
I&amp;rsquo;m generally not a fan of the idea of &amp;lsquo;building a career&amp;rsquo; - generally when I hear that phrase it involves having a &amp;lsquo;five year&amp;rsquo; plan and other such concepts which I consider to be pointless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linchpin: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 16:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a couple of Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s other books - Tribes and The Dip - and found them fairly readable so I figured his latest offering, Linchpin, would probably be worth a read too.
This is the first book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the iPad&amp;rsquo;s Kindle application and it was a reasonably good reading experience - I particularly like the fact that you can make notes and highlight certain parts of the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maverick: Book review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 07:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>My colleagues Frankie and Danilo have been recommending &amp;lsquo;Maverick&amp;rsquo; to me for a long time and I finally got around to reading it.
In this book Ricardo Semler, the CEO of Semco, tells the story of the company and how he helped evolved the organisation into one which is more employee led and embraces ideas such as open &amp;amp; self set salaries while encouraging civil obedience in the workforce as a necessity to alert the organisation to its problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting real: Book review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 21:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across 37 Signals &amp;lsquo;Getting Real&amp;rsquo; book where they go through their approach to building web applications and there have certainly been some good reminders and ideas on the best way to do this.
These are some of my favourite parts:
 Ship it!  If there are minor bugs, ship it as soon you have the core scenarios nailed and ship the bug ﬁxes to web gradually after that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Lecture - Randy Pausch</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 14:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Last Lecture: Achieving Your Childhood Dreams&amp;rsquo; and read the corresponding book and although it&amp;rsquo;s not directly related to software development I think that some of the points that he makes are really intriguing.
These were some of the parts that particularly stood out for me:
 Introduce the elephant in the room - whatever it is that people are really thinking about, put it out in the open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug It: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 05:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</guid>
      <description>David Agans&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; is the best debugging book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so I was intrigued to see that there was another book being written on the subject.
Paul Butcher offered me a copy of the book to review so I was keen to see whether it was more like &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Release It&amp;rsquo; as Ted Neward suggests.
The Book Debug It by Paul Butcher
The Review Much like Krzysztof Kozmic I found that a lot of the ideas early on in the book were similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught by my ThoughtWorks colleagues over the last 3 1&amp;frasl;2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UML: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite recent blog posts is one written by Sammy Larbi on coupling and cohesion and while discussing it with Phil he suggested that I would probably like this book and in particular the chapter on connascence which I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written about.
The Book Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UML by Meilir Page-Jones
The Review I really enjoyed reading this book and I think it&amp;rsquo;s one that I could come back and read again to gain something else from in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Mind, Beginners Mind: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/12/zen-mind-beginners-mind-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 09:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/12/zen-mind-beginners-mind-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Zen Mind, Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Mind by Shunryu Suzuki
The Review I first came across the actual term beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind when reading through the &amp;lsquo;Wear The White Belt&amp;rsquo; chapter of Apprenticeship Patterns although it was often mentioned to me on one of the first projects I did at ThoughtWorks a couple of years ago that people liked teaching me things because I just took the information in pretty much without questioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield Application Development in .NET: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/07/06/brownfield-application-development-in-net-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/07/06/brownfield-application-development-in-net-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Brownfield Application Development in .NET by Kyle Baley and Donald Belcham
The Review I asked to be sent this book to review by Manning as I was quite intrigued to see how well it would complement Michael Feather&amp;rsquo;s Working Effectively with Legacy Code, the other book I&amp;rsquo;m aware of which covers approaches to dealing with non green field applications.
What did I learn?  The authors provide a brief description of the two different approaches to unit testing - state based and behaviour based - I&#39;m currently in favour of the latter approach and Martin Fowler has a well known article which covers pretty much anything you&#39;d want to know about this topic area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Arguments and Results (James Noble)</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/book-club-arguments-and-results-james-noble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/book-club-arguments-and-results-james-noble/</guid>
      <description>We restarted our book club again last week by reading James Noble&amp;rsquo;s Arguments and Results paper, a paper I came across from a Michael Feathers blog post a few months ago detailing 10 papers that every programmer should read.
We decided to try out the idea of reading papers/individual chapters from books as it allows us to vary the type of stuff we&amp;rsquo;re reading more frequently and is an approach which Obie seems to be having some success with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real World Functional Programming: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Real World Functional Programming by Tomas Petricek with Jon Skeet (corresponding website)
The Review I decided to read this book after being somewhat inspired to learn more about functional programming after talking with Phil about his experiences learning Clojure. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a .NET project so it seemed to make sense that F# was the language I picked to learn.
What did I learn?  I&#39;ve worked with C# 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>97 Things Every Software Architect Should Know: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/18/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 01:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/18/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book 97 Things Every Software Architect Should Know by Richard Monson-Haefel
The Review My colleague Erik Doernenburg mentioned that he had written a couple of chapters in this book a while ago and there was a copy of the book in the ThoughtWorks office so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a look.
I&amp;rsquo;m far from being an architect but since their decisions affect what I do I was intrigued to see what they should be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Dysfunctions of a Team: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/22/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 06:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/22/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book The Five Dysfunctions of a Team by Patrick Lencioni
The Review I heard about this book a while ago but I was intrigued to actually get a copy by Darren Cotterill, the Iteration Manager on the project I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.
I was particularly interested in learning whether the ideas of agile and/or lean help to solve any of these dysfunctions.
What did I learn?  The book is split into two sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mythical Man Month: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/11/the-mythical-man-month-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/11/the-mythical-man-month-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book The Mythical Man Month by Fred Brooks Junior
The Review Pretty much since I started working at ThoughtWorks 2 1&amp;frasl;2 years ago I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that this is a book I have to read and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around to doing so.
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not that surprising but my overriding thought about the book is that just about every mistake that we make in software development today is covered in this book!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/21/lean-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 10:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/21/lean-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Lean Thinking by James P. Womack and Daniel T. Jones
The Review This is the latest book in my lean learning after The Toyota Way, Taiichi Ohno&amp;rsquo;s Workplace Management and Lean Software Development and seemed like the most logical one to read next as it came at lean from a slightly different angle.
I found this the most hard going of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the subject so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-reading books</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/19/re-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 10:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/19/re-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>An interesting thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to notice recently with regards to software development books is that I get a lot more from reading the book the second time compared to what I did reading the book the first time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed this for several books, including The Pragmatic Programmer, Code Complete and Domain Driven Design, so my first thought was that perhaps I had read this books too early when I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the necessary context or experience to gain value from reading them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell
The Review I came across this book following recommendations by Jason Yip and Steven &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; List on Twitter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously read The Tipping Point and Blink and I like his easy going style so it was a no brainer that I was going to read this one.
I found that this book complimented Talent is Overrated quite nicely. Outliers covers how the story of how people became the best at what they do whereas Talent is Overrated focuses more on what you need to do if you want to become one of these people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent is Overrated: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 20:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Talent is Overrated by Geoff Colvin
The Review I came across this book on Jason Yip&amp;rsquo;s Twitter feed while the idea of 10,000 hours to become an expert at any given skill was being discussed. I&amp;rsquo;m reading Outliers as well and the two books seem to complement each other quite well.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in how we can apply deliberate practice in software development, perhaps using the medium of coding dojos, to become better developers in a more effective manner than just normal practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Software Development: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/20/lean-software-development-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 17:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/20/lean-software-development-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Lean Software Development by Mary and Tom Poppendieck
The Review I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn how the ideas from The Toyota Way can be applied to software development and as far as I know this is the first book which addressed this, hence the reason for me reading it.
What did I learn?  I found the idea of financial based decisions particularly interesting - I&#39;ve often had situations when developing software where there are trade offs to make and it would have been much easier to make them if we had a dollar value associated with each potential solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiichi Ohno&#39;s Workplace Management: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 00:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Taiichi Ohno&amp;rsquo;s Workplace Management by Taiichi Ohno
The Review Having completed The Toyota Way a few weeks ago I was speaking with Jason about what books were good to read next - he recommended this one and The Toyota Way Fieldbook.
I struggled to see a connection to software development with a lot of what I read, but there were certainly words of wisdom that we can apply to continuously improve our ability to deliver projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toyota Way: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/19/the-toyota-way-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 06:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/19/the-toyota-way-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book The Toyota Way by Jeffrey Liker The Review
I was initially very skeptical about the value of lean in software development but became intrigued as to its potential value after listening to Jason championing it. Since The Toyota Way is the book where many of the ideas originated from I thought it only made sense for this to be my first port of call to learn about lean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Clear: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 08:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Crystal Clear by Alistair Cockburn
The Review This was a book which had been recommended to me by a colleague a few months ago as one of the best software development books to read, and after hearing Ian Cooper describe how his team was implementing some of the ideas at the Alt.NET conference I decided I&amp;rsquo;d give it a read.
I have been working in an Agile/XP environment at ThoughtWorks for the last two years so my context coming into the book was around understanding where the overlap with Crystal Clear was, what differences there are and how I can apply these on my projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearless Change: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 23:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Fearless Change by Mary Lyan Manns and Linda Rising
The Review I came across this book while watching an interview with Linda Rising on InfoQ. She mentioned some ideas from Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s The Tipping Point which intrigued me and a strong recommendation from a colleague ensured this book made it onto my reading list.
I am not currently working on a project where I need to instigate a lot of change so I was going slightly against my own principle of only reading books when I need to, but I recalled several times previously when I have tried to introduce what I thought were good ideas and didn&amp;rsquo;t really get anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Driven Development By Example: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/07/test-driven-development-by-example-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 23:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/07/test-driven-development-by-example-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Test Driven Development by Example by Kent Beck
The Review I know this book is quite old but I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it before - it&amp;rsquo;s been recommended to me several times but I never got round to reading it, possibly because of my somewhat misguided opinion that seeing as I do TDD nearly every day I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to read it.
More by chance than anything else, I was browsing through a friend&amp;rsquo;s copy of the book and came across several gems of information which persuaded me that I should take the time to read the rest of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Learning and Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 02:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Pragmatic Learning and Thinking by Andy Hunt
The Review I came across this book when reading a post linking lean to the Dreyfus Model on Dan North&amp;rsquo;s blog.
I have a keen interest in theories of learning and have completed an NLP Practitioner&amp;rsquo;s course so the ideas described in the book summary immediately appealed to me.
After coming across the concept of Reading Deliberately in Chapter 6 of the book I decided I should give the SQ3Q approach to reading books its first run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Code: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/15/clean-code-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 10:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/15/clean-code-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book Clean Code by Robert &#39;Uncle Bob&#39; Martin The Review I first heard of Uncle Bob a couple of years ago in a conversation with Obie Fernandez and having previously read his Agile Principles, Patterns and Practices in C# book, when my colleague Alexandre Martins came back from JAOO Sydney raving about a talk on &amp;lsquo;Clean Code&amp;rsquo; he&amp;rsquo;d seen I knew I had to buy this book when it came out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Productive Programmer: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/05/the-productive-programmer-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/05/the-productive-programmer-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Book The Productive Programmer by Neal Ford The Review I first came across this book when I was browsing Andy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware on Amazon. It showed up as one of the related books.
I had expected it to be a more theoretical book than it actually is. It is full of really useful command line tips and ways to use system tools and IDEs more effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>