<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Badass: Making users awesome - Kathy Sierra: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2015/03/20/badass-making-users-awesome-kathy-sierra-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Extract topics for HIMYM corpus -&amp;gt; Train a topic model with mallet -&amp;gt; Tweak an existing topic model that uses mallet -&amp;gt; Run an existing topic model that uses mallet -&amp;gt; Install mallet </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Thing About Hard Things - Ben Horowitz: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 23:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2014/10/13/the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Horowitz suggests that he used to be too positive and would shield bad news from his employees as he thought he&amp;rsquo;d make the problem worse by transferring the burden onto them.
He came to the realisation that this was counter productive since he often wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best placed person to fix a problem e.g. if it was a problem with the product then the engineering team needed to know so they could write the code to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Fast and Slow - Daniel Kahneman: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 22:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/10/27/thinking-fast-and-slow-daniel-kahneman-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Kahneman points out that we only remember the intuitions which turned out to be true, noone talks about those intuitions which turned out to be false. He also cautions us to consider the role that luck plays in any success.In the world of software this reliance on intuition is often used when interviewing people for jobs and choosing who to hire based on an intuitive judgement. Kahneman suggests making a list of about 6 traits that are pre-requisites for the position and then ranking each candidate against those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well - William Zinsser: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 22:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/09/30/on-writing-well-william-zinsser-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found this to be the case multiple times although you can achieve the same benefits by presenting a talk on a topic; the benefits aren&amp;rsquo;t unique to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 algorithms that changed the future - John MacCormick: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/08/13/9-algorithms-that-changed-the-future-john-maccormick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise that Sergey Brin and Larry Page had published a paper back in 1998 titled &amp;lsquo;The Anatomy of a Large-Scale Hypertextual Web Search Engine&amp;rsquo; which explains the initial PageRank algorithm in more detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Signal and the Noise - Nate Silver</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2013/05/14/book-review-the-signal-and-the-noise-nate-silver/</guid>
      <description>The book mainly focuses on the latter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Retrospective Handbook - Pat Kua</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 21:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/08/31/book-review-the-retrospective-handbook-pat-kua/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Pat Kuarecently published a book he&amp;rsquo;s been working on for the first half of the year titled &amp;lsquo;The Retrospective Handbook&amp;rsquo; - a book in which Pat shares his experiences with retrospectives and gives advice to budding facilitators.
I was intrigued what the book would be like because the skill gap between Pat and me with respect to facilitating retrospectives is huge and I&amp;rsquo;ve often found that experts in a subject can have a tendency to be a bit preachy when writing about their subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 21:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/12/18/the-lean-startup-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d heard about The Lean Startupfor a long time before I actually read it, mainly from following the &amp;lsquo;Startup Lessons Learned&amp;rsquo; blog, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the book until a colleague suggested a meetup to discuss how we might apply the ideas on our projects.
My general learning from the book is that we need to take the idea of creating tight feedback loops, which we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt in the agile/lean worlds, and apply it to product development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing the Undiscussable: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/07/discussing-the-undiscussable-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I came across the work of Chris Argyris at the start of the yearand in a twitter conversation with Benjamin Mitchellhe suggested that Bill Noonan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Discussing the Undiscussable&amp;rsquo; was the most accessible text for someone new to the subject.
In the book Noonan runs through a series of different tools that Chris Argyrisoriginally came up with for helping people to handle difficult conversational situations more effectively.
I really like the way the book is written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books: Know why you&#39;re reading it </title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/books-know-why-youre-reading-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 03:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/02/26/books-know-why-youre-reading-it/</guid>
      <description>Something which I frequently forget while reading books is that it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite useful to know exactly why you&amp;rsquo;re reading it i.e. what knowledge are you trying to gain by doing so.
I noticed this again recently while reading The Agile Samurai- it&amp;rsquo;s one of the books we ask ThoughtWorks Universityparticipants to read before they come to India.
Implicitly I knew that I just wanted to get a rough idea of what sort of things it&amp;rsquo;s telling people but I somewhat foolishly just started reading it cover to cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures of Johnny Bunko -  The Last Career Guide You&#39;ll Ever Need: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 17:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/21/the-adventures-of-johnny-bunko-the-last-career-guide-youll-ever-need-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I read Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s A Whole New Mindearlier in the year but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of The Adventures of Johnny Bunkountil my colleague Sumeet Moghementioned it in a conversation during ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s XConf, an internal conference run here.
The book is written in the Mangaformat so it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly quick to read and it gives 6 ideas around building a career.
I&amp;rsquo;m generally not a fan of the idea of &amp;lsquo;building a career&amp;rsquo; - generally when I hear that phrase it involves having a &amp;lsquo;five year&amp;rsquo; plan and other such concepts which I consider to be pointless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linchpin: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 16:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/07/12/linchpin-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a couple of Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s other books - Tribesand The Dip- and found them fairly readable so I figured his latest offering, Linchpin, would probably be worth a read too.
This is the first book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the iPad&amp;rsquo;s Kindle applicationand it was a reasonably good reading experience - I particularly like the fact that you can make notes and highlight certain parts of the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maverick: Book review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2010 07:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/04/14/maverick-book-review/</guid>
      <description>My colleagues Frankieand Danilohave been recommending &amp;lsquo;Maverick&amp;rsquo; to me for a long time and I finally got around to reading it.
In this book Ricardo Semler, the CEO of Semco, tells the story of the company and how he helped evolved the organisation into one which is more employee led and embraces ideas such as open &amp;amp; self set salaries while encouraging civil obedience in the workforce as a necessity to alert the organisation to its problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting real: Book review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2010 21:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/03/08/getting-real-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across 37 Signals &amp;lsquo;Getting Real&amp;rsquo; book where they go through their approach to building web applications and there have certainly been some good reminders and ideas on the best way to do this.
These are some of my favourite parts:
Often on projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on we&amp;rsquo;ve taken the approach that bugs get worked on before new stories which makes sense in a way because it means that we are fixing problems quickly and keeping the quality of the application high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Lecture - Randy Pausch</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 14:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/01/01/the-last-lecture-randy-pausch/</guid>
      <description>I recently watched Randy Pausch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Last Lecture: Achieving Your Childhood Dreams&amp;rsquo; and read the corresponding bookand although it&amp;rsquo;s not directly related to software development I think that some of the points that he makes are really intriguing.
These were some of the parts that particularly stood out for me:
While I think they&amp;rsquo;re certainly right I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that learning theory before putting it into practiceis the most effective way to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug It: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 05:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/24/debug-it-book-review/</guid>
      <description>David Agans&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; is the best debugging book that I&amp;rsquo;ve read so I was intrigued to see that there was another book being written on the subject.
Paul Butcher offered me a copy of the book to review so I was keen to see whether it was more like &amp;lsquo;Debugging&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Release It&amp;rsquo; as Ted Neward suggests.
Debug Itby Paul Butcher
Much like Krzysztof KozmicI found that a lot of the ideas early on in the book were similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve been taught by my ThoughtWorks colleagues over the last 3 1/2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UML: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/12/01/fundamentals-of-object-oriented-design-in-uml-book-review/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite recent blog posts is one written by Sammy Larbi on coupling and cohesionand while discussing it with Philhe suggested that I would probably like this book and in particular the chapter on connascence which I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written about.
Fundamentals of Object-Oriented Design in UMLby Meilir Page-Jones
I really enjoyed reading this book and I think it&amp;rsquo;s one that I could come back and read again to gain something else from in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen Mind, Beginners Mind: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/12/zen-mind-beginners-mind-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 09:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/08/12/zen-mind-beginners-mind-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Zen Mind, Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Mindby Shunryu Suzuki
I first came across the actual term beginner&amp;rsquo;s mindwhen reading through the &amp;lsquo;Wear The White Belt&amp;rsquo; chapter of Apprenticeship Patternsalthough it was often mentioned to me on one of the first projects I did at ThoughtWorks a couple of years ago that people liked teaching me things because I just took the information in pretty much without questioning.
I find nowadays that I analyse what people tell me way a lot more and then compare it against what I already know to see if it adds to my understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownfield Application Development in .NET: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/07/06/brownfield-application-development-in-net-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/07/06/brownfield-application-development-in-net-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Brownfield Application Development in .NETby Kyle Baley and Donald Belcham
I asked to be sent this book to review by Manning as I was quite intrigued to see how well it would complement Michael Feather&amp;rsquo;s Working Effectively with Legacy Code, the other book I&amp;rsquo;m aware of which covers approaches to dealing with non green field applications.
I often end up over complicating code in an attempt to create &amp;lsquo;abstractions&amp;rsquo; but by this definition I&amp;rsquo;m not really abstracting since I&amp;rsquo;m not simplifying but complicating!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Club: Arguments and Results (James Noble)</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/book-club-arguments-and-results-james-noble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/06/16/book-club-arguments-and-results-james-noble/</guid>
      <description>We restarted our book club again last week by reading James Noble&amp;rsquo;s Arguments and Results paper, a paper I came across from a Michael Feathers blog post a few months ago detailing 10 papers that every programmer should read.
We decided to try out the idea of reading papers/individual chapters from books as it allows us to vary the type of stuff we&amp;rsquo;re reading more frequently and is an approach which Obie seems to be having some success with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real World Functional Programming: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/24/real-world-functional-programming-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Real World Functional Programmingby Tomas Petricek with Jon Skeet (corresponding website)
I decided to read this book after being somewhat inspired to learn more about functional programming after talking with Philabout his experiences learning Clojure. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a .NET project so it seemed to make sense that F# was the language I picked to learn.
module Tests = let WithIncome (f:Func&amp;lt;_, _&amp;gt;) client = { client with Income = f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>97 Things Every Software Architect Should Know: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/18/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 01:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/05/18/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-book-review/</guid>
      <description>97 Things Every Software Architect Should Knowby Richard Monson-Haefel
My colleague Erik Doernenburgmentioned that he had written a couple of chapters in this book a while ago and there was a copy of the book in the ThoughtWorks office so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a look.
I&amp;rsquo;m far from being an architect but since their decisions affect what I do I was intrigued to see what they should be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Dysfunctions of a Team: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/22/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 06:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/22/the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Five Dysfunctions of a Teamby Patrick Lencioni
I heard about this book a while ago but I was intrigued to actually get a copy by Darren Cotterill, the Iteration Manager on the project I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.
I was particularly interested in learning whether the ideas of agile and/or lean help to solve any of these dysfunctions.
I think lean/agile ideas do solve some of the problems but certainly not all of them and it would definitely be interesting to try out some of the exercises suggested on future teams I work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mythical Man Month: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/11/the-mythical-man-month-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/04/11/the-mythical-man-month-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Mythical Man Monthby Fred Brooks Junior
Pretty much since I started working at ThoughtWorks 2 1/2 years ago I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that this is a book I have to read and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around to doing so.
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not that surprising but my overriding thought about the book is that just about every mistake that we make in software development today is covered in this book!
In other words&amp;hellip;Domain Driven Design!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/21/lean-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 10:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/21/lean-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Lean Thinkingby James P. Womack and Daniel T. Jones
This is the latest book in my lean learning after The Toyota Way, Taiichi Ohno&amp;rsquo;s Workplace Managementand Lean Software Developmentand seemed like the most logical one to read next as it came at lean from a slightly different angle.
I found this the most hard going of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the subject so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-reading books</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/19/re-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 10:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/03/19/re-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>An interesting thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to notice recently with regards to software development books is that I get a lot more from reading the book the second time compared to what I did reading the book the first time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed this for several books, including The Pragmatic Programmer, Code Completeand Domain Driven Design, so my first thought was that perhaps I had read this books too early when I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the necessary context or experience to gain value from reading them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2009/01/06/outliers-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Outliersby Malcolm Gladwell
I came across this book following recommendations by Jason Yipand Steven &amp;lsquo;Doc&amp;rsquo; Liston Twitter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously read The Tipping Point and Blink and I like his easy going style so it was a no brainer that I was going to read this one.
I found that this book complimented Talent is Overratedquite nicely. Outliers covers how the story of how people became the best at what they do whereas Talent is Overrated focuses more on what you need to do if you want to become one of these people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talent is Overrated: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 20:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/29/talent-is-overrated-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Talent is Overratedby Geoff Colvin
I came across this book on Jason Yip&amp;rsquo;s Twitter feedwhile the idea of 10,000 hours to become an expert at any given skill was being discussed. I&amp;rsquo;m reading Outliersas well and the two books seem to complement each other quite well.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in how we can apply deliberate practice in software development, perhaps using the medium of coding dojos, to become better developers in a more effective manner than just normal practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Software Development: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/20/lean-software-development-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2008 17:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/20/lean-software-development-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Lean Software Developmentby Mary and Tom Poppendieck
I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn how the ideas from The Toyota Waycan be applied to software development and as far as I know this is the first book which addressed this, hence the reason for me reading it.
I am keen to see how the authors suggest introducing some of these ideas in Implementing Lean Software Development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiichi Ohno&#39;s Workplace Management: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 00:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/12/09/taiichi-ohnos-workplace-management-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Taiichi Ohno&amp;rsquo;s Workplace Managementby Taiichi Ohno
Having completed The Toyota Way a few weeks ago I was speaking with Jasonabout what books were good to read next - he recommended this one and The Toyota Way Fieldbook.
I struggled to see a connection to software development with a lot of what I read, but there were certainly words of wisdom that we can apply to continuously improve our ability to deliver projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toyota Way: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/19/the-toyota-way-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 06:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/19/the-toyota-way-book-review/</guid>
      <description>The Toyota Wayby Jeffrey Liker
I was initially very skeptical about the value of lean in software development but became intrigued as to its potential value after listening to Jasonchampioning it. Since The Toyota Way is the book where many of the ideas originated from I thought it only made sense for this to be my first port of call to learn about lean.
I was worried that the book wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that applicable to me as a software developer but I was able to see the parallels between how what we do and what is done in manufacturing have similarities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Clear: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 08:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/11/05/crystal-clear-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Crystal Clearby Alistair CockburnThis was a book which had been recommended to me by a colleague a few months ago as one of the best software development books to read, and after hearing Ian Cooperdescribe how his team was implementing some of the ideas at the Alt.NET conferenceI decided I&amp;rsquo;d give it a read.
I have been working in an Agile/XP environment at ThoughtWorks for the last two years so my context coming into the book was around understanding where the overlap with Crystal Clear was, what differences there are and how I can apply these on my projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fearless Change: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 23:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/21/fearless-change-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Fearless Changeby Mary Lyan Manns and Linda Rising
I came across this book while watching an interview with Linda Rising on InfoQ. She mentioned some ideas from Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s The Tipping Pointwhich intrigued me and a strong recommendation from a colleagueensured this book made it onto my reading list.
I am not currently working on a project where I need to instigate a lot of change so I was going slightly against my own principle of only reading books when I need to, but I recalled several times previously when I have tried to introduce what I thought were good ideas and didn&amp;rsquo;t really get anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Driven Development By Example: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/07/test-driven-development-by-example-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 23:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/07/test-driven-development-by-example-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Test Driven Development by Exampleby Kent BeckI know this book is quite old but I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it before - it&amp;rsquo;s been recommended to me several times but I never got round to reading it, possibly because of my somewhat misguided opinion that seeing as I do TDD nearly every day I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to read it.
More by chance than anything else, I was browsing through a friend&amp;rsquo;scopy of the book and came across several gems of information which persuaded me that I should take the time to read the rest of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Learning and Thinking: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 02:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/10/06/pragmatic-learning-and-thinking-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Pragmatic Learning and Thinkingby Andy HuntI came across this book when reading a post linking lean to the Dreyfus Modelon Dan North&amp;rsquo;s blog.
I have a keen interest in theories of learning and have completed an NLP Practitioner&amp;rsquo;s courseso the ideas described in the book summary immediately appealed to me.
After coming across the concept of Reading Deliberately in Chapter 6 of the book I decided I should give the SQ3Qapproach to reading books its first run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Code: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/15/clean-code-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 10:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/15/clean-code-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I first heard of Uncle Bob a couple of years ago in a conversation with Obie Fernandezand having previously read his Agile Principles, Patterns and Practices in C#book, when my colleague Alexandre Martinscame back from JAOO Sydneyraving about a talk on &amp;lsquo;Clean Code&amp;rsquo; he&amp;rsquo;d seen I knew I had to buy this book when it came out.
In a good trend which I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed in a lot of Martin Fowler books, Uncle Bob lays out in the opening chapter how he thinks the book can best be read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Productive Programmer: Book Review</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/05/the-productive-programmer-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/05/the-productive-programmer-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I first came across this book when I was browsing Andy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetwareon Amazon. It showed up as one of the related books.
I had expected it to be a more theoretical book than it actually is. It is full of really useful command line tips and ways to use system tools and IDEs more effectively. It only took until page 3 for me to learn something from this book - a short cut for navigating Firefox tabs which I now use all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>