<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Retrospectives on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/retrospectives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retrospectives on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 18:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/retrospectives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: An alternative safety check</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/10/27/retrospectives-an-alternative-safety-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 18:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2012/10/27/retrospectives-an-alternative-safety-check/</guid>
      <description>At the start of most of the retrospectives I&amp;rsquo;ve been part of we&amp;rsquo;ve followed the safety check ritual whereby each person participating has to write a number from 1-5 on a sticky describing how they&amp;rsquo;ll be participating in the retrospective.
1 means you&amp;rsquo;ll probably keep quiet and not say much, 5 means you&amp;rsquo;re perfectly comfortable saying anything and the other numbers fall in between those two extremes.
In my experiences it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a fruitless exercise because its viewed that a higher number is &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo; and therefore the minimum people will tend to write down is &amp;lsquo;3&amp;rsquo; because they don&amp;rsquo;t want to stand out or cause a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: The 4 L&#39;s Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/07/25/retrospectives-the-4-ls-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 21:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/07/25/retrospectives-the-4-ls-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>I facilitated the latest retrospective my team had last week and decided to try The 4 L&amp;rsquo;s technique which I&amp;rsquo;d come across while browsing the &amp;lsquo;retrospectives&amp;rsquo; tag on del.icio.us.
We had 4 posters around the room representing each of the L&amp;rsquo;s:
 Liked Learned Lacked Longed for  I&amp;rsquo;m not really a fan of the majority of a retrospective being dominated by a full group discussion as many people aren&amp;rsquo;t comfortable giving their opinions to that many people and therefore end up not participating at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: Mini Group Discussions</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/03/20/retrospectives-mini-group-discussions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 18:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/03/20/retrospectives-mini-group-discussions/</guid>
      <description>One of the approaches that I like the best in retrospectives is when the facilitator splits the team into smaller groups during the brainstorming part of the retrospective.
I decided to try this out in a retrospective we ran after one week of ThoughtWorks University, using The Retrospective Starfish to provide a framework in which people could frame their thoughts.
Usually what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen happen in these mini groups is that everyone will write down their own ideas on stickies and then discuss them as a group but still put up all the stickies even if the group didn&amp;rsquo;t agree with everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: My first time facilitating</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/15/retrospectives-my-first-time-facilitating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/15/retrospectives-my-first-time-facilitating/</guid>
      <description>Despite being part of numerous retrospectives over the past few years I don&amp;rsquo;t remember actually facilitating one until my current team&amp;rsquo;s last week.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gradually come to appreciate the skill involved in facilitating this type of meeting having originally been of the opinion that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to it.
I recently read Agile Retrospectives which has loads of different ideas for activities beyond just creating &amp;lsquo;went well&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;could improve&amp;rsquo; columns and then filling those in as a group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: General observations</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/06/retrospectives-general-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 17:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/06/retrospectives-general-observations/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my blog post about some observations about the actions that we create in retrospectives I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed some general ways that retrospectives might not end up being as useful as we&amp;rsquo;d hope.
Having a manager facilitating While having the manager of the team facilitating the retrospective isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem in itself I think it&amp;rsquo;s useful to remember that in this context they aren&amp;rsquo;t in that role anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: Actions</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/06/retrospectives-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 11:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/06/retrospectives-actions/</guid>
      <description>My colleague Ashwin Raghav wrote a blog post earlier in the week in which he noted some patterns that he&amp;rsquo;s noticed in retrospectives in his time working in ThoughtWorks.
In it he talks quite generally about things he&amp;rsquo;s noticed but in my experience one of the areas in which teams typically struggle is when it comes to action items.
Too many action items I think this is probably the number one mistake that we make in retrospectives and it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospectives: Some thoughts</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/10/retrospectives-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 07:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/06/10/retrospectives-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on two different teams this year which had quite different approaches to retrospectives.
In the first team we had a retrospective at the beginning of every iteration i.e. once every two weeks and in the second team we tried out the idea of having a rolling retrospective i.e. we put up potential retrospective items on the wall and when there were enough of those we discussed them in the standup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of Crowds and groupthink in Agile Software Development</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2008/09/03/the-wisdom-of-crowds-and-groupthink-in-agile-software-development/</guid>
      <description>Gojko Adzic posted a summary of a talk James Surowiecki gave at Agile 2008 and it got me thinking how we use the Wisdom of Crowds in Agile projects.
One of the most interesting things I learnt from the book is that when you bring together a diverse group of people, their output will probably be better than any one expert. Gojko points out this example that was used at Agile 2008:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>