<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XP Day on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/xp-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XP Day on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 02:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/category/xp-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Visualizing what&#39;s happening on our project</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/30/xp-day-visualizing-whats-happening-on-our-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 02:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/30/xp-day-visualizing-whats-happening-on-our-project/</guid>
      <description>Another presentation that I gave at XP Day was one covering some visualisations Liz, Uday and I have created from various data we have about our project, gathered from Git, Go and Mingle.
Visualisations
These were some of the things that I learned from doing the presentation:
The various graphs I presented in the talk have a resolution of 1680 x 1050 which is a much higher resolution than what was available on the projector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Scala: An Experience Report (Liz Douglass and me)</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-scala-an-experience-report-liz-douglass-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 23:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-scala-an-experience-report-liz-douglass-and-me/</guid>
      <description>At XP Day my colleague Liz Douglass and I presented the following experience report on our last 6 months working together on our project.
Scala: An experience report
We wanted to focus on answering the following questions with our talk:
Should the project have been done in Java?
Does it really speed up development as was hoped?
What features of the language and patterns of usage have been successes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Cynefin &amp; Agile (Joseph Pelrine/Steve Freeman)</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-cynefin-agile-joseph-pelrinesteve-freeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 22:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/24/xp-day-cynefin-agile-joseph-pelrinesteve-freeman/</guid>
      <description>Another session that I attended at XP Day was one facilitated by http://twitter.com/!/sf105[Steve Freeman] and http://twitter.com/!/josephpelrine[Joseph Pelrine] where we discussed the Cynefin model, something that I first came across earlier in the year at XP 2011.
We spent the first part of the session drawing out the model and coming up with some software examples which might fit into each domain.
Simple - when you’re going to checkin run the build</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XP Day: Refactoring to functional style (Julian Kelsey/Andrew Parker)</title>
      <link>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/22/xp-day-refactoring-to-functional-style-julian-kelseyandrew-parker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.markhneedham.com/blog/2011/11/22/xp-day-refactoring-to-functional-style-julian-kelseyandrew-parker/</guid>
      <description>I’m attending XP Day this year and the first talk I attended was one by Julian Kelsey and Andrew Parker titled &amp;#39;Refactoring to functional style&amp;#39;.
I’ve worked on a Scala project for the last 6 months and previously given a couple of talks about adopting a functional style of programming in C# so this is a subject area that I find quite interesting.
The talk focused on 5 refactorings that the presenters have identified to help move imperative code to a more functional style:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
