<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems Thinking 2 on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/systems-thinking-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems Thinking 2 on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 23:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://markhneedham.com/blog/tag/systems-thinking-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming the system: Some project examples</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/10/26/gaming-the-system-some-project-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 23:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/10/26/gaming-the-system-some-project-examples/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year Liz Keogh gave a talk at QCon London titled &amp;lsquo;Learning and Perverse Incentives: The Evil Hat&amp;rsquo; where she eventually encouraged people to try and game the systems that they take part in.
Over the last month or so we&amp;rsquo;ve had two different metrics visibly on show and are therefore prime targets for being gamed.
The first metric is one we included on our build radiator which shows how many commits to the git repository each person has for that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounded Rationality</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/06/26/bounded-rationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 17:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/06/26/bounded-rationality/</guid>
      <description>In &amp;lsquo;Thinking In Systems: A Primer&amp;rsquo; one of the most interesting ideas that Donella Meadows describes is what Herbert Simon coined &amp;lsquo;bounded rationality&amp;lsquo;:
 Bounded rationality means that people make quite reasonable decisions based on the information they have. But they don&#39;t have perfect information, especially about more distant parts of the system  Later on in the chapter the following idea is suggested:
 If you become a manager, you probably will stop seeing labour as a deserving partner in production, and start seeing it as a cost to be minimised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;In what world does that make sense&#34;</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/14/in-what-world-does-that-make-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 21:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/14/in-what-world-does-that-make-sense/</guid>
      <description>In her keynote at XP 2011 Esther Derby encouraged us to ask the question &amp;ldquo;in what world does that make sense?&amp;rdquo; whenever we encounter something which we consider to be stupid or ridiculous.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it at the time but my colleague Pat Kua has been asking me the question whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve been describing something that I find confusing to him.
After about the third time I noticed that its quite a nice tool for getting us to reflect on the systems and feedback loops that may be encouraging the behaviour witnessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Traps: Rule Beating</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/14/system-traps-rule-beating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 21:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/14/system-traps-rule-beating/</guid>
      <description>In &amp;lsquo;Thinking In Systems&amp;rsquo; section five focuses on systems which produce &amp;ldquo;truly problematic behaviour&amp;rdquo; and one of these so called system traps is known as &amp;lsquo;rule beating&amp;rsquo;.
Rule beating occurs when the agents in a system take evasive action to get around the intent of rules in a system:  The letter of the law is met, the spirit of the law is not. 
A common system where we see this in organisations is around training budgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback Loops: Human Decisions</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/05/feedback-loops-human-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 18:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/05/05/feedback-loops-human-decisions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Donella Meadows&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Thinking In Systems: A Primer&amp;rsquo;, an introductory text on systems thinking, and after 30 pages or so the author poses the following challenge:
 Sometimes I challenge my students to try to think of any human decision that occurs without a feedback loop - that is, a decision that is made without regard to any information about the level of stock that it influences  Meadows has quite a nice way of guiding us to thinking about systems by referring to &amp;lsquo;stocks&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;flows&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Argyris: Espoused Theory vs Theory in Action</title>
      <link>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/13/chris-argyris-espoused-theory-vs-theory-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 20:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/13/chris-argyris-espoused-theory-vs-theory-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Via some combination of Christian Blunden, Pat Kua, David Joyce and Benjamin Mitchell I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time lately reading about the work of Chris Argyris.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously come across his name while reading The Fifth Discipline but I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise how interesting his work actually is.
One of the interesting concepts I&amp;rsquo;ve come across so far is the difference between espoused theory and theory in use:
Espoused theory  The world view and values people believe their behaviour is based on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>