<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distributed Agile on Mark Needham</title>
    <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/category/distributed-agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distributed Agile on Mark Needham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 03:34:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://markhneedham.com/blog/category/distributed-agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Stories -  Negotiable</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/distributed-agile-stories-negotiable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 03:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2011/01/24/distributed-agile-stories-negotiable/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading an article about how to write meaningful user stories and towards the end of it the author mentioned the INVEST acronym which suggests that stories should be:
 Independent Negotiable Valuable Estimable Small Testable  From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the most difficult one to achieve in a distributed context is that stories should be &amp;lsquo;negotiable&amp;rsquo;, in particular when it comes to negotiating the way that the UX of a bit of functionality should work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Cultural Differences: Hierarchy</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/27/india-cultural-differences-hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 14:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/27/india-cultural-differences-hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>One of the more interesting differences between Indian culture and my own is that in India there appears to be more adherence to a hierarchy than I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced before.
ThoughtWorks tries to keep a reasonably flat hierarchy so I think the idea of hierarchy would be much more obvious if I was working at one of the big Indian services organisations.
Between peers conversations don&amp;rsquo;t seem to play out any differently but someone in a position of authority is more likely to be able to get their opinion across and accepted with less resistance than they might experience without that authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Cultural Differences: Language</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/24/india-cultural-differences-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/24/india-cultural-differences-language/</guid>
      <description>For the majority of the time that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent in Pune so far language hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a big deal at all but there are a couple of differences that I didn&amp;rsquo;t initially anticipate.
The local language While the official office language is English my colleagues seem more comfortable talking to each other in Hindi so quite frequently the conversation will move into Hindi if someone isn&amp;rsquo;t directly speaking to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Cultural Differences: Stretched work day</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/20/india-cultural-differences-stretched-work-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 21:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/20/india-cultural-differences-stretched-work-day/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago I briefly touched on the very stretched days I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced while working in India.
This is in contrast to what I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in the UK and Australia where the day was much more time boxed and tended to go from 9am to 6pm.
At the moment we also have a call with colleagues in Chicago at 9pm for about 30-45 minutes so the day has now stretched out until nearly 10pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Bringing onshore people offshore</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/20/distributed-agile-bringing-onshore-people-offshore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 08:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/20/distributed-agile-bringing-onshore-people-offshore/</guid>
      <description>For the last two weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve had a ThoughtWorks colleague from the onshore team working with us in Pune and it&amp;rsquo;s been really cool having someone who has been working on &amp;lsquo;the other side&amp;rsquo;.
In my time in India there seem to have been many more people going from offshore to onshore than the other way around but based on this experience I don&amp;rsquo;t think that should necessarily be the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India Cultural Differences: Tolerance/Patience</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/15/india-cultural-differences-tolerancepatience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 19:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/15/india-cultural-differences-tolerancepatience/</guid>
      <description>Some colleagues have been asking me recently what cultural differences I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed working in India compared to my experiences in the UK and Australia and one of the biggest differences by far is the amount of tolerance and patience people here have compared to me.
These attributes seem to show themselves in roughly two situations:
With respect to the environment We&#39;ve had some building work done in the Pune office recently which has meant that there&#39;s been extremely high volume drilling being done to the extent that you can barely hear someone who&#39;s sitting a couple of metres away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Other observations</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/12/distributed-agile-other-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 08:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/12/12/distributed-agile-other-observations/</guid>
      <description>Some of the difficulties of working in an offshore environment were clear to me before I even came to India but I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a few others lately which I either didn&amp;rsquo;t think about before or didn&amp;rsquo;t realise how annoying they were!
Getting data from the client&amp;rsquo;s network For several of the stories that we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on lately we needed to make use of huge amounts of reference data residing on the client&amp;rsquo;s network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Communicating big design decisions</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/10/distributed-agile-communicating-big-design-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 19:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/10/distributed-agile-communicating-big-design-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Although we mostly split the work on my project so that there aren&amp;rsquo;t too many dependencies between the teams in Chicago and Pune, there have still been some times when we&amp;rsquo;ve designed major parts of the code base in Pune and have needed to communicate that to our Chicago colleagues.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen this situation so it&amp;rsquo;s been interesting to see which approaches work in trying to do this effectively and allowing the people in the other location to have input as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Communication - Reliance on one person</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/08/distributed-agile-communication-reliance-on-one-person/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 13:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/11/08/distributed-agile-communication-reliance-on-one-person/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with my series of observations on what it&amp;rsquo;s like working in a distributed agile team, another thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed is that it&amp;rsquo;s useful to try and ensure that there is communication between as many people as possible in the two cities.
This means that we want to ensure that we don&amp;rsquo;t have an over reliance on one person to handle any communication.
We have a call once a day between developers in Pune and Chicago and the Chicago guys have been able to achieve this by rotating the person attending the call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Context</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/31/distributed-agile-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 18:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/31/distributed-agile-context/</guid>
      <description>From my last couple of months working for ThoughtWorks in Pune I think the most common subject that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard discussed is how to ensure that the team offshore is receiving all the context about the decisions and direction being taken onshore.
What I&amp;rsquo;ve found most interesting is that I think out of all the teams that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on in the last four years my current team has by far the most context about what the client wants to do and the approaches they want to take over the next few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Communication</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/27/distributed-agile-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 13:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/27/distributed-agile-communication/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d always heard that communication when you&amp;rsquo;re working offshore was much more difficult than in a co-located team but it&amp;rsquo;s quite difficult to imagine exactly what the difficulties are until you see them for yourself.
These are some of my latest observations in this area so far.
Learning models I&#39;m a very visual learner and the majority of the time any communication between people in two different locations will be done through words either via email or on a conference call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Physical story wall still useful</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/20/distributed-agile-physical-story-wall-still-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 17:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/20/distributed-agile-physical-story-wall-still-useful/</guid>
      <description>When I started working on my current project there was no physical story wall, instead the whole project was being tracked on Mingle.
The current state of the Mingle story wall was sometimes visible on a shared monitor and sometimes wasn&amp;rsquo;t, depending on whether or not the monitor had been turned off.
There was also a small wall used to track which stories were in development but after that there was no physical visibility of the status of anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Cultural Differences/Expectation disconnect</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/17/distributed-agile-cultural-differencesexpectation-disconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 15:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/10/17/distributed-agile-cultural-differencesexpectation-disconnect/</guid>
      <description>I came across an article written a few months ago titled &amp;lsquo;Outsourcing doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&amp;rsquo; which discussed some of the problems the author has experienced while working with teams offshore.
The article is provocatively titled but has some interesting observations which I thought I could contrast with my own after working offshore in Pune, India for a couple of months now.
The team I&amp;rsquo;m working on is distributed between Pune and Chicago so it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the same situation as the author&amp;rsquo;s but the majority of the team are in a different country to the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Agile: Initial observations</title>
      <link>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/23/distributed-agile-initial-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 02:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markhneedham.com/blog/2010/08/23/distributed-agile-initial-observations/</guid>
      <description>One of the reasons I wanted to come and work for ThoughtWorks in India is that I wanted to see how a distributed agile project is run and see the ways in which it differs to one which is done co-located.
I worked on a project which was distributed between Sydney and Melbourne in 2008&amp;frasl;2009 and while some of the challenges seem to be quite similar to the ones we faced there, some are completely different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>